<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non-Tech on Himanshu Mishra</title>
    <link>https://orkohunter.net/categories/non-tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Non-Tech on Himanshu Mishra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Himanshu Mishra</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://orkohunter.net/categories/non-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We should write notes (for life lessons)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/we-should-write-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/we-should-write-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my JEE preparations, I used to make a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of notes. Everyone did. Our Physics teacher was a storyteller. His stories used to make me wonder. I used to write them down as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I studied for two years. Thus, it was very important to write things down and keep revising. It was impossible to remember the lessons we learnt, without making good notes. My academic journey is about to end with my graduation. I realize I would not be making any notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I was listening to an amazing podcast called &lt;a href=&#34;https://secularbuddhism.com/episodes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Secular Buddhism&lt;/a&gt;. One of the episodes made my day. I need to remember the concept in the future as well. But, I am sure I will forget this in a month or earlier. This is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We should be making non-academic notes as well&lt;/strong&gt;. The podcast episode was like a lesson, and it is a very good idea to write it down. The writing process will also add clarity to my understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have conversations daily. We experience many things. We read books. We meditate. We observe things silently. All this time, we learn something, the quality and amount of which is subjective. Sometimes, we ponder over one thought for days to understand it upto satistication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any other lesson, we should keep re-visiting these thoughts. This is necessary to generate value for our future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an incredible case of note taking. There is no ultimate exam. Yet, some days may create an illusion of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geniune Love and Infatuation</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/love-and-infatuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/love-and-infatuation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long time, I read something so meaningful on reddit. &lt;strong&gt;How do you distinguish genuine love for someone from infatuation?&lt;/strong&gt; was the question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I want to quote what I read and later express some of my thoughts on the subject. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/AskMen/comments/aedq0v/how_do_you_distinguish_genuine_love_for_someone/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here is the original comment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; It’s really easy to confuse it with genuine love. But for me anyway, infatuation is a lot more like a drug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a feeling that consumes you with temporary euphoric highs, and deep, dark lows. It’s almost like a panicked state of obsession. It fills your brain so all you can think about is that person. You start to care less about what really matters in your own life&amp;hellip;your goals, your friends, your work. All that matters when you’re infatuated, is them. And you feel a strong, leeching desire to mold yourself into the person you think they’d want you to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re infatuated with someone, when that person gets closer to you in any way, you feel a rush. Like you’re on cloud 9. Like you just popped a bunch of really good ecstasy. And it feels amazing in the moment. But then when you sense them distancing from you in any way&amp;hellip;an ignored text. A rescheduled date. Flirting with another person. Going out on the town without you. Whatever. It feels like the world is crumbling&amp;hellip;like you’re going through a withdrawal. You panic and fear you’re going to lose them. There’s a constant push/pull. In those moments of panic all you care about is pulling them back to you. Those up and downs can be maddening over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, I think infatuation is latching onto the idealized picture your brain paints of someone. &amp;hellip; You feel in love with them even though you barely know what’s it like to really be with them. &amp;hellip; You start thinking crazy thoughts like “this person is perfect”&amp;hellip;”this person is the solution to all of my problems, if I can just keep them I’ll be fulfilled”&amp;hellip;”if I can’t have this person I’ll never be genuinely happy”. You think you’re madly in love. But it’s all shallow. Once that person actually starts getting closer to you&amp;hellip;the infatuation can wear off pretty quickly&amp;hellip;and you can be left feeling confused and deflated. Like a spent firework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think most “love at first sight”, and honeymoon periods is really just infatuation. It can turn into love, but it’s not really. And sometimes if you’re not careful, it can blind you and drag you down into some really dark places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love on the other hand, is a lot more comfortable. It’s less erratic. It grows slowly over time and stays pretty constant. Its the general feeling of caring and warmth towards someone. You can hate someone in a current moment, but still love them overall. You can find someone to be unattractive, or incompatible&amp;hellip;and still love them deep down. You can have a fight with the person you love, and not fear you’re going to lose them&amp;hellip;you just want to revolve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not like a drug&amp;hellip;it doesn’t have the highs and lows of infatuation. Its gotta be cultivated and nurtured. You don’t lose yourself in it, or have the drive to turn into the person they want you to be&amp;hellip;love helps you find yourself, and drives you to become the person you want to be. Love for a partner isn’t too different than the love you feel for a blood relative. It can be subtle and mellow&amp;hellip;sometimes barely recognizable&amp;hellip;but it’s always there. You’re connected to them at a deep primal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This left me thinking for some time. Some of my thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have little control over our Infatuation, but Love is a practice&lt;/strong&gt;. It is comforting to know that love is not a fixed biological property which is set since birth. It is so much about our choices. We can learn to love and become one with it. We can teach people to practice love. Infact, there exists a very profoud meditation technique called &amp;ldquo;Loving-Kindness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People can sometimes fall in love with their infatuation but never the person&lt;/strong&gt;. This is so interesting to think about! This can give someone a feeling of being in love. But as the infatuation fades, the love fades as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infatuation is not bad at all&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s as if, infatuation is our survival mechanism. But love goes beyond just surviving. It is spiritual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Love is not an emotion&lt;/strong&gt;. Happiness and Sadness come in phases. They are emotions. But love is always present, in us. Our mind may get distracted sometimes. (This is whole another perception, which I felt in one experience.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Love is very fundamental and not complicated&lt;/strong&gt;. Day passes by and my definition of love keeps getting shorter. Something so easy to experience, so difficult to express.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>और तसवीरें आने को हैं न !</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/aur-tasveerein/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/aur-tasveerein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;जो इन रंगों से कागज़ तुम सजाते हो,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो ये सुन्दर रंग-चित्र तुम बनाते हो,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तुम्हारे मन में अभी&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;और तसवीरें आने को हैं न !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो मधुर गीत ये तुम सुनाते हो,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;धुन ये प्यारी गुन गुनाते हो,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तुम्हारे दिल में अभी &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;और तरंगें बजने को हैं न !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो ये प्यारी बातें उसे बताते हो,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो ये सुन्दर सपनें खुदको दिखाते हो,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तुम्हारी ज़िन्दगी में&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कितना और सोचने को है न !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कलम को कागज़ से यूँ लगाते हो,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो रोज़ तुम कविताएँ नयी बनाते हो,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तुमको अभी और&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कितना कुछ लिखने को है न !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/threads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/threads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’re an interesting species. An interesting mix. You’re capable of such beautiful dreams, and such horrible nightmares. You feel so lost, so cut off, so alone, only you’re not. See, in all our searching, the only thing we’ve found that makes the emptiness bearable, is each other.” — Carl Sagan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always wonder when I listen to this quote in the song &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7AoJwMImQZE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Doves by We Are All Astronauts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my college, I have never walked up to a complete stranger and ended up being friends. It is hard for most people to do so. No matter how much we understand the importance of interacting with new people, mostly in the early years of our lives, it is not an easy thing to do. In my freshmen year, I never knocked the doors of my neighbors or any of my wingmates to learn about them. It was a conscious decision. But I now realize, there wasn’t a random to-be-friend knock on my door either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many years and friendships later, I can now understand that between me and any of my friends, there is always one common “thread.” It can be the Literary Society (TLS), or the Open Source folks, or the ones from KOTA, or my wing-mates, post-rock music, department, being intoxicated together, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For two unacquainted people to start a conversation, it is a bit difficult to talk directly about each other. It won’t even go well. But it becomes relatively simple if they talk about anything that they have in common. And then they always remember that thread connecting them for the next few meetups until they don’t need the reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing how many threads KGP creates in our lives, to give us friendships for lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain, Mind and Consciousness — Essay</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/brain-mind-and-consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/brain-mind-and-consciousness/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layers of ‘I’ when perceiving anything which is external to it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Montaigne, one of the first essay writers, for popularizing this literary genre. As the title suggests, I have had many musings upon the similarity and the differences of these three entities which can be thought as a subset of ‘&lt;em&gt;I’&lt;/em&gt; and which have very diffused boundaries among their definitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: The following ideas are highly subjective. I would not advise the reader to consider them factual. Also, instead of focusing too much on the scientific details, the reader should try to read the hints to what I’m trying to communicate by using language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;let-s-define&#34;&gt;Let’s Define&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cogito ergo sum (I think therefore I am) — René DescartesThe entity ‘I’ or ‘Me’ is a strange topic of discussion. While some people would oversimplify this to the human body, others might overcomplicate and make this is a subject of spiritual mysticism. I want to remain sane on this topic and probably write the words which can make sense in daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the majority of ‘I’ is divided into three parts or layers, namely the Brain, the Mind and the Consciousness. The Brain is the outermost layer, the frontier of the Self. Take a scenario for example. You are reading this text. The first ‘You’ is your eyes, receiving colorful light rays from the screen. The ‘You’ then converts this information into electrical signals for further processing. This part is called Brain. It is an entirely physical entity, made of matter which interacts with the outer world through our senses, i.e., sight, touch, smell, taste, and sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Brain is very close to a computer program, and vice versa. It is programmed to execute in a definite manner. When given a set of inputs, it runs the required number and type of processes and is done with it. It encounters bugs in its lifetime which causes the dysfunctioning of some module. It also has a computing power and needs resources such as oxygen and food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Brain then tries to pass this information to our Consciousness but in comes the Mind. The Mind is that child of ours, whom we love so much that we probably can never stop listening to. The Mind constitutes of our thoughts, our emotions associated with those thoughts, reactions and Ego. If you have disliked this essay so far, your brain has nothing to do with it; it just is feeding the information to your Mind, which is sitting only to judge the content. The Mind will then react and ask your Brain (followed by the senses) to either continue or stop reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://orkohunter.net/img/1*G7iss0cgkvwcZuBdvvjXmw.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘I’ in terms of processing an informationWe can look at the Mind as a semi-physical entity. On one side it shares boundaries with the physical bodies like sensations and hormones, while on the other hand, it has slight access to the metaphysical entities inside us which are hard to define as matter, i.e., Consciousness and Ego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://orkohunter.net/img/1*6IXNzi_k8lbhFVaLm-8WFg.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of perceivable matter in each entityThe Consciousness is the purest form of ‘I,’ which does not think, which does not react, which does not speak with our mouth, which does not listen with our ears, which does not recognize anything as good or bad, pleasant or unpleasant. It is a thoughtless entity. It can interchangeably be understood as ‘the energy of life’. If you have ever been a psychonaut, this is the ‘vibration’ part of self, and it does communicate to other consciousness. If your consciousness is unaware of something which only your brain and mind knows (Take the statement ‘*We should love everyone*’ for example), it is entirely possible that you might react unexpectedly in extreme situations, contradictory to what you think you should never have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-chariot&#34;&gt;The Chariot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you remember the scene from the epic Mahabharat? During the battle scene, the chariot with the most attention was of Arjun. Now there’s a great symbolism to be drawn from the setting. There is Arjun with all the weapons, perplexed with the myriad of thoughts about the battle, sitting on a chariot with Krishna, who is calm and patiently replying to all of the questions thrown by Arjun. Krishna is also the charioteer, holding the reins. There are horses driving the chariot, and finally, there’s the battleground, the vast ground where the chariot can roam around and interact with other chariots and other entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collectively if we are to compare this one picture with ‘I,’ the chariot is similar to a Body. Arjun is like the Mind having all of its thoughts, ego, and confusions. Krishna is the inner Consciousness. The reins connect the Mind with the horses, which are to be interpreted as the senses we use to interact with the external world, which here is the entire battleground of Kurukshetra. The ‘I’ functions when everything is at their place, resonating in perfect coordination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all the questionnaire (popularly known as Bhagavad Gita), Krishna drives the chariot and is only capable of waking Arjun up and channeling all of his powers. I don’t know how reliable this symbolism should be held but loosely it’s very similar to the game of Mind and Consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;change&#34;&gt;Change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How are these entities altered?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the Brain is straightforward. One can close their eyes, put on earphones with music and there, the state of their Brain is now different. But closing the eyes does not mean the person shall stop thinking about it. The change in Brain has little to no effects on the Mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the Mind is a tedious process. It requires expertise to govern thoughts from coming in and going out. It is a long process to gain control over one’s Ego. These methods can be classified under various Meditative techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the Consciousness makes you a Psychonaut. A Psychonaut is a person who experiences intentionally induced altered states of consciousness and claims to use the experience to investigate his or her Mind, and possibly address spiritual questions, through direct experience. A change in Consciousness will, by default, reflect on the Mind and the Brain as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people talk about Enlightenment, they mean altered Consciousness and not a new Mind. All the humans feel love, sadness, hate, anger, etc., every single one of us and is, in fact, one of the traits which define us. A monk in the Himalayas is undoubtedly not deprived of Mind, but they probably know how to open up with the Consciousness directly and not let Mind be a middle-man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enlightenment doesn’t care how we reach there. — Thaddeus GolasThe consciousness can be altered with prolonged meditation (very subjective to the technique and the person). The use of naturally occurring mushrooms containing psilocybin, DMT, LSD and many other psychedelic and psychoactive substances can also challenge Consciousness to its very core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;communication&#34;&gt;Communication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if there is any test to know whether some information which was thrown at us, has reached our consciousness or not. Merely hearing it ensures Brain level perception. Pondering over it as a thought provides that it is floating in our Mind. But how can we know if our Consciousness is aware of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one practice which can make sure the thought isn’t stuck in the Mind. The method is to “Avoid Overthinking.” Overthinking is terrible. It is a risky business. On the one hand, it opens up new insights to a thought, on the other side it leads to the loss of reality and makes it very hard for any information to escape from our Minds. Another good practice is to not letting our Ego come into the picture. We can do it by not allowing our subjective feelings and judgment interfere while we catch a piece of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing that ‘I’ can be dissolved into these three entities can have very positive effects while communicating with others. If we can see that our words will be reflected by their layer of Ego, there is no way we can deliver our message to them despite speaking for any length of time, since it will never reach their Consciousness. We can then find out the correct choice of words to avoid their shiny surface of Mind which is eager to reflect anything that is thrown towards it such that it pierces through and reaches their Consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, we have the tendency to solve a problem with another person, just by speaking to them. Example can be a conflict of interest with our parents, friends or a significant other. But it’s wise to understand that the situation might have left the Mind of the other person very confused, and it’s best not to talk since our words will quickly bounce off them. It’s better to sit back, wait, till they work out with their Mind and are ready to communicate. Interesting to note that this is counter-intuitive to our Minds which quickly reacts by blabbering out whatever we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-not-my-thoughts&#34;&gt;I am not my Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is “watching the breath” one of the first and simplest meditation techniques? During Vipassana, it is suggested to start first by the practice of watching the whole breathing cycle and rather focus on the nostrils. This is not Vipassana, but it acts as an anchor to calm the Mind so that we would be able to do the actual practice. We can give an analogy of the mind to that of a chattering monkey. The Mind usually does not shut up and keeps feeding us with thoughts, ego, and their effects. We then tell the Mind, “O hey! Do you see this? Do you see me inhaling and exhaling? It’s beautiful, isn’t it? Watch!”. It’s like giving a crying baby, a toy to play with and making her come at ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we start watching our thoughts, we begin to accept, and later appreciate the meaninglessness of them. Merely by watching them come and go, we build up a tolerance for a reaction, and it stops us from engaging from them in the future. We learn how futile are our thoughts, opinions, and judgments. Often at times, people are afraid of meaninglessness, which makes them value their thoughts very much. This makes them misinterpret that they are their thoughts, and thus, they build up a thick layer over their Consciousness, which is another meaningless and thoughtless entity. There is a possibility that life gets more beautiful if we stop yearning for everything to be meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ego&#34;&gt;Ego&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ego is a word which has been overstated and misunderstood a lot of times. Never is one’s true ego positive or negative, it’s the thoughts associated with it. A negative thought pattern can be removed while keeping the Ego intact. We just can’t let it happen very easily, since it’s so powerful. Ego is the ID of the Mind; it’s what makes us respond to someone calling our name. It might sound blissful to live after ‘Ego Death’, but that’s not how anyone can survive. Killing one’s ego is killing Self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If ego death isn’t desirable, then what is? Here is a comment from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Psychonaut/comments/43oysz/how_is_ego_death_beneficial/czjv2nn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;/r/Psychonaut&lt;/a&gt; which I find very relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I don’t believe complete Ego death is possible, or even desirable. What I suggest is mastery of the Ego. Think of it like a wild animal to be tamed instead of destroyed. It is a part of you, an integral and important one, in fact, but for most people, it’s grown monstrous and completely out of control. Or put differently, it is in full control. And so we become passengers in these meat machines, with the Ego at the wheel. Dangerous stuff!
The Ego is only the Ego so long as it remains distinct and separate from the rest of you. The process we should undergo is what Carl Jung called individuation: the uniting of a fractured mind, of a psyche, compartmentalized and segregated into individual parts; the merging of conscious and unconscious, Self and Ego, reasoning mind and intuitive mind. The result is that we become indivisible, whole, balanced, and more importantly, in control.
How does this benefit you? Well, imagine two pilots wrestling for control of the ship. Good luck getting to your destination! Or better yet, good luck agreeing on a target. Before individuation, we’re torn and divided, conflicted and confused. We’re being driven, not doing the driving, you see? The Ego wants one thing, the Self another, and then it’s a battle for control. Or else the Ego is whispering sweet lies, and the Self is buying them wholesale so that the Self comes to believe that it and the Ego are one. This is a nice little tactic by the Ego, and one that can be observed in people on a daily basis. Defensiveness is an obvious indication of Ego identification. What are you defending? An opinion? A belief? A role? These things are not you, only things you do or things you cling to, but the Ego grows strong from false identification and so pokes and prods you into getting your back up whenever these are called into question.
How do you merge with the shadow? The first step is identifying it in yourself by distinguishing between the essential you — the Self, or pure consciousness — and the stuff that isn’t you. By watching your thoughts, words, and actions, seeking out incoherence and contradictions, defensiveness and sore spots, and then calling these into question. Be harsh with yourself. And whatever you do, don’t shy away from the ugly bits: that’s where the Ego likes to hide out.### Ignorance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t we hate it when we write or speak all the facts and support our argument while the person on the other side just &lt;em&gt;chooses&lt;/em&gt; to ignore those and raises some of their own? It is happening every second on Facebook and Twitter comments section, and it’s eating out a lot of Brains. But why do people choose to be ignorant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment we add our entire Mind in the equation of &lt;em&gt;thought process&lt;/em&gt;, it by default, includes the sensations in our body, emotional reactions, opinions, and separately, the Brainly activities, i.e., Reading/Listening and Writing/Speaking. Now, the Brain has no trouble in receiving any argument, neither the Consciousness has; but it’s the Mind, and if the words are causing any unpleasant sensations, we tend to reject it. And that’s where we lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No sensation is either good or bad. However, it &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; arise. It’s natural for all of us. The key is not in ceasing it, but accepting it, accepting that impermanence is a real thing. The sensations have come, only to pass away. It has no real meaning, and we should not be trying to give it any value. We indulge in reactions too often and thus end up losing the direct communication with our Consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;consciousness&#34;&gt;Consciousness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, we only know the tip of the iceberg known as Consciousness. I am very impressed by Yuval Noah Harari’s understanding of the consciousness and the scientific aspects of it, written in his book &lt;em&gt;Homo Deus&lt;/em&gt;. To me, understanding one’s consciousness is a very complicated subject since it’s very easy to overthink it. It is the subjective ability to experience. Anything can be an experience, merely sitting somewhere alone in lush green, or talking to a person, or watching the leaves fall from a tree, anything and everything can become an experience and our consciousness is responsible for the subjective aspects of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not capable of writing about it. I’m not capable of using terms like ‘Vibration’ and ‘Energy’ to describe it. But I secretly wish, for a scientific explanation in centuries when we’d be pondering over the consciousness of Artificial Intelligence. Even if I can see things as it is (it’s the literal meaning of &lt;em&gt;Vipassana&lt;/em&gt;), I wish things to be proven for a systematic understanding by the humanity. Wait, what is String Theory &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DeleteFacebook</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/delete-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/delete-facebook/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://orkohunter.net/img/1*0l-9QfuqEhDiBumKeTmGuQ.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After letting Facebook Inc. build a vast profile of me for 9 years, I deleted my facebook account. Privacy is not my &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; concern, but I &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@OrkoHunter/the-discovery-of-pseudo-acquaintance-9f903601d916&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;personally reacted&lt;/a&gt; to how Facebook has affected &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/20/16800842/facebook-2017-russia-scandal-news-feed-criticism-defectors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the way we interact in our real life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Downloaded a copy of my data from facebook -&amp;gt; settings
This contained all of my messages, photos, videos, and probably a lot more information which I can not consciously recall sharing with Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Created a dummy facebook account* and added it to the resourceful groups I might miss out important information from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*An account without any interaction i.e. No likes, No reactions neither love nor angry, no comments, no photos/videos, no “friends”. A profile to just receive information on email (sent by facebook).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/help/delete_account&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/help/delete_account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Going extreme) Blocked Facebook servers on my computer that my computer can never communicate to domain names linked to Facebook servers. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jmdugan/blocklists/tree/master/corporations/facebook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;social-concerns&#34;&gt;Social concerns&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People started using Facebook as LinkedIn by adding Freinds and it blurred the lines of relationships between two individuals — &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@OrkoHunter/the-discovery-of-pseudo-acquaintance-9f903601d916&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real addiction to unreal things — &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/3ev7GXzFTPg?t=3m10s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook (read &lt;em&gt;Social Media&lt;/em&gt;) promotes Ignorance by thoughtless comments, replies and reactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;privacy-concerns&#34;&gt;Privacy concerns&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will suffice — &lt;a href=&#34;https://stallman.org/facebook.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://stallman.org/facebook.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Discovery of pseudo-Acquaintance</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/pseudo-acquaintance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/pseudo-acquaintance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s the dawn of the 20th century. If we pick two homo sapiens on earth, we can classify their relationship as one of these three types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Acquaintance (Both of them are acquainted with each other)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unfamiliarity (No one knows about the existence of other)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Celebrity status (One of the two is famous)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is the dawn of the 21st century. And every day in my college I meet few people who fall in none of the three types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day I see people on 2.2, whom I know by face and name, as well as they know me and my name. But we don’t stop to say, ‘Hi’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These are my &lt;em&gt;pseudo-acquaintances&lt;/em&gt; whom I got to know from Facebook.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the deal. Somewhere in the data centers of Facebook Inc, there is a matrix which stores the connection between two nodes, and the edge value of those people and me is True. There have been numerous CSS divs containing strings which either they or I have written, which got a click from the other, sometimes a further div of “comment” as well. Somehow, subconsciously my brain understood that a person and I had interacted a whole bunch and thus we are friends. But when the same mind physically spots them in public, that same person for the first time in months, there is no surge of emotions to go and talk to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know someone on Facebook, I “interact” with them, but I don’t speak with the same passion or eagerness to them in real life, using flesh and bones. For me, it is terrifying. What if people eventually stop using their mouth for conversations because Whatsapp and Messenger let them use that gif meme to convey more efficiently. What if we discover some other app or platform to express ourselves in the best way which is different than meeting the person and using our mouth, eyes, face, hands or smile to express?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the fact that the first world countries already have incorporated a bit of this culture, raises merely questions about parenting. What if we are not concerned about our children, and the first friend they make, do not physically exist around them. I am surely, not saying one is better than others; there are so many pros of the Scientific Revolution, Internet being a tiny monster of it. I am just saying that, are people responsible? Is Facebook responsible enough to know that it has created an illusion of friendships and relationship and does it care about it? From the weekly product and feature launches, for the sole purpose of us interacting more on their platform, and increasing their value as advertisers and not looking up from our phones, I think it does not care at all. Or is it in control of anyone to care about it? Something like a trained Deep Learning model, over which we only have very few control after some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt; This article above was an email to a few close friends, right after I realized my first pseudo-acquaintance. I am thankful to their responses, they made me rethink every bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been quite long since I joined Facebook.com and I have spent a lot of time with the product. I have met and stayed connected with a lot of people using this platform, and therefore, I am probably thankful for it. However, here is my current setup, as of now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t use the product ‘news feed’. I use a version of News Feed Eradicator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ran a custom Javascript script to unfollow all of my Facebook friends and then turned on the notifications for few, as I deemed necessary in my real life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the phone, I do not have the Facebook app and I use messenger with the setting where I do not receive any notification (interrupts) but I would instead open the app to see if there any new messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing that I want to say is that there are mostly no good and no wrong sides. As a human, we always have to use our discretion and find something in between. Hence I can not blindly delete Facebook to solve this problem, I’ll have to see the way to use it for my productivity, as long as it doesn’t consume a lot of my time to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Update, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@OrkoHunter/deletefacebook-10f365c5d36e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I deleted my Facebook account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quest for Universal action — Essay</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/quest-for-universal-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/quest-for-universal-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may listen to this while reading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/-fFbeSykaJk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few months ago, a significant percentage of my peers were involved in the process of getting a job or an internship, including me. Some got the &lt;em&gt;success&lt;/em&gt; while some are still trying. But to my astonishment, I found that the degree of comfort in each one of them was not as expected. What I mean by that is, not everyone who got this success was happy, and not everyone who failed was sad, although the majority was skewed on the side of the former case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I broadened my perspective and timeframe, I found that getting a job which pays in money, is not something which can give satisfaction to every human being. We cannot universally advise this to everyone. If you think so, then please understand the gravity of human population on this planet, and my concern was about satisfaction which is difficult to define, since a large part of it loses touch with materialism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I aligned my line of thought with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;loving the work we do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If a farmer spends the day on their field, and they enjoy it, then it’s good, isn’t it? How about the software engineer who thinks their technology can help people or maybe due to some other reason, they find love in the code, they write? I found that it was closer to being a ubiquitous activity which can keep people happy, or at least a large number of humans. But then, I saw people who do not have any job at first place. By &lt;em&gt;job&lt;/em&gt;, I mean an activity which benefits people and provides something (&lt;em&gt;e.g. salary&lt;/em&gt;) in return for the individual. But there are wanderers, &lt;em&gt;fakirs&lt;/em&gt;, hitchhikers and many types of &lt;em&gt;unemployed&lt;/em&gt; people. So, are they different from &lt;em&gt;regular&lt;/em&gt;? These people challenged the universality of this line of thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It further gave me an idea that instead of (or along with) loving the work, we also need to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;enjoy with the peers who surround us&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. So, a lot of human beings are embraced by their parents, friends and/or children. It does not happen always, but we can still find some of these in different bandwidths of our life. It reminded me of the letter by Richard Feynman, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lettersofnote.com/2015/10/do-not-remain-nameless-to-yourself.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Do not remain nameless to yourself&lt;/a&gt;. So yeah, Living in love can be a universal thing to do. And it allowed me to picture this massive population of ours on the planet earth. But then, I found exceptions. I thought of Chris McCandless (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Into_the_Wild_%28film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Into the wild&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and how he did not find love in his family but Nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://orkohunter.net/img/1*nVDd-ZNwdd9EGJ3iLxpEzg.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;A scene from the movie Into the WildI was back to square one. Do we need another human being to live this life, happily? People can not always surround us. And further, outside of seven billion humans, there are other lives as well. What about dogs, or the trees, plants, and flowers which are alive? Or a lost animal somewhere in the jungle. Do they have to have a peer to share the love or their &lt;em&gt;pursuit of happiness&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My problem set got bigger, and I appreciated &lt;em&gt;how difficult it must be for a democracy to form its constitution&lt;/em&gt; or King Hammurabi to write his &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_of_Hammurabi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;. At this point, I felt a little exhausted in finding the answer to my question (it had been several months by now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a few days ago, as I was practicing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vipassan%C4%81#Vipassana-meditation_in_the_modern_Vipassana_movement&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vipassana Meditation&lt;/a&gt;, I had an epiphany about the question. I realized how much did I miss to observe about my own physical body even when there was so much going on already. I never noticed my breath on its whole (trust me, when I say, I still have not). The moment we start to breathe in, and it goes on for a full length, and then it stops. A moment of no activity, and then we breathe out. And the cycle repeats. Breathing is just one of the many involuntary signs of life, and yet it goes on unnoticed. It made me regard the totality around me, even more. To mention a few, the breeze which blows past me when I stroll on &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.metakgp.org/w/2.2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2.2&lt;/a&gt;, the distant sound I listen to while typing this text, the leaves which fall off from the trees when I sit with a cup of &lt;em&gt;chai&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.in/maps/place/Bhaski%27s/@22.3161081,87.2988514,21z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x3a1d43feddbb1c35:0xeff718f07e02348!8m2!3d22.3159891!4d87.2987071&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bhaski’s&lt;/a&gt;, and other many signs of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think, for the question of &lt;em&gt;“What is something which should be the universal action of everyone?”&lt;/em&gt;, I can put it in words as “&lt;em&gt;To witness”&lt;/em&gt;. We necessarily do not have to think, question, or react to the activities around us or &lt;em&gt;even inside us&lt;/em&gt;, but to just witness the presence of life. In Sanskrit, we call this state of no-mind as निर्विचार. I felt that generally, we are ignorant of ourselves and we miss to observe a lot. With this awareness and focus, the decisions we make are quite apparent, and we can then work on optimizing our limited time on this planet to do something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>धुआं (Dhuaan)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/dhuaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/dhuaan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ग़र्द उड़ाते उन पहियों को &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हर सांझ हथेली मार - मार&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सड़कें जो नापी सब ने ;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उस धुएं में छुपे&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सत्य की परवाह थी क्या किसे ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ढलते उसी वक्त में &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;चूल्हे में गोयठे सुलगाती &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हज़ारों बार आँखें सेंकी ;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन अगणित माताओं के&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नयनों की परवाह थी क्या किसे ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्मुक्त मित्र-मंडलियों संग &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जब धुएं में विलुप्त अंतर्मन &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;फिरदौस की सैर हम करते ;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तब दिल में उस बुझते&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्रेम की परवाह थी क्या किसे ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मसान के मंदभाग्य भूमि पे &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पिता से अंतिम सीख लेते&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जब धुएं-स्वरुप अलोप रहा बचपन;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तब घर में छूटे आखिरी&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;निवाले की परवाह थी क्या किसे ?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I hate my friends on Instagram?</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/instagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/instagram/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Watch this video from Nerdwriter1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/eQzmLrSjmhg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; Facebook, but only with a different purpose than &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10100933624710391&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;connecting people&lt;/a&gt;, it’s about sharing photos. Photos are great, they convey art, beauty and literature in its own form. And that is what attracted Instagram to so many users. But the problem started when, we applied our *minds to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-instagram-should-never-be-about&#34;&gt;What Instagram should never be about&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharing pictures with your face in it&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://orkohunter.net/img/1*JKA3w0kD0GzK9xMizjjhrQ.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;Couple years ago, if you had clicked a great picture of yours and you wanted to share it among your friends (people who know you), you’d usually go to Facebook and then share it over there. But what people do now is that they post it on Instagram and then share it over Facebook. This is the most meaningless aspect of Facebook after pokes. Why do you expect someone to see (follow) your photos on Instagram if they do not know you at all? And if they do, you are definitely friends with them on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poorly composed pictures clearly showing you having fun&lt;/strong&gt;
Why do people start migrating away from Facebook? This happened when their friends started using Facebook as a &lt;em&gt;PR tool&lt;/em&gt;, to estabilish that they are living a good life, irrespective of the reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what would happen if you would post your party pictures, your fun trips stories on Instagram? Don’t they already have enough from you, on Facebook?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-fix-it&#34;&gt;How to fix it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting Nerdwriter1 here, “Before posting anything on the social media, think a little about Why you post what you post.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can have all of Flickr, 500px, Imgur on Instagram, with a better and more familiar social network. But like &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://reddit.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; and unlike &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quitfacebookday.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, it is &lt;strong&gt;okay&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;not to&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;post,&lt;/em&gt; but just consume the beauty out of it. So, put the peer pressure off and enjoy following &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creativebloq.com/photography/instagram-2131996&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some amazing photographers&lt;/a&gt; on Instagram. And hey, it’s perfectly cool if you share your photography skills over there too ! It’s a social network after all. And it’s also alright if you click a cute picture of a child you spotted in a village. It’s great. Likeways, it’s okay if you post a picture of your own child. Or your spouse. Or your own. Hey wait, maybe I should watch the video again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Facebook-sick 
**It’s okay to post a picture of a Human (and it’s not the same)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t actually hate my friends on instagram. It’s just a momentary disgust, which vanishes away when I hangout with these amazing people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आंसुओं के बिंब से छलकती हुई दुनिया, देखी थी मैंने एक बार</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/aanshuon-ke-bimb-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/aanshuon-ke-bimb-se/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आंसुओं के बिंब से छलकती हुई दुनिया, देखी थी मैंने एक बार&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वक्त की गहराईयों में डूबती नज़र आई थी वो&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;नज़रों से सहारा दिया मैंने&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ख़ुशी का भरोसा दिया मैंने&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;न जाने मेरा हाथ क्यों न थामाँ उसने&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उसे गहराइयों की सुकूँ भाती चली गयी ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Sandeep Jha for the first two lines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erotomania : An Unfortunate Tale</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/erotomania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/erotomania/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Hey Wake up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wake up, for you are left with just 30 more minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You better sleep after this is over; rather that would be your only choice. Just 30 minutes later, when the crescent rays will fall on the black hood covering your face, when you’ll be tied with, or rather “in” a knot, for the second time of your life, believe me you would not want to be in haste. You don’t want them to see your eyes popped out, or your filthy tongue stuck out like a creep right? So, get up, go get your hair combed, your teeth cleaned, and most importantly collect as much happy thoughts as possible in your stupid brain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only child of his parents, this kid was a loner, an antisocial introvert who liked to stay back in his shady living-slash-playing room, and wished to stay there for lifetime. Skipping school since the fourth grade, his mother very well accepted his social awkwardness as well as his mind’s disability and was happy with hiding it from the rest of the world. Whilst I, I watched him grow, I kept calling out for him, in his good times, or bad. I lived in him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he was 10, his mother was relocated to a new place, around 50 kilometres from the capital, a place where neighbourhood was as far as the corner shop in the hometown. He was terrified. He had to greet the visitors all along. It was then, he met his first friend, a girl. After she came into his life, there was no shady place, in his house, or heart or anywhere. &lt;em&gt;‘I love when Vaidehi blinks and smiles at the same time’&lt;/em&gt;, he’d say to his mom. One day, it was evident to him, that Vaidehi had the most beautiful eyes he’d ever seen. I still remember how his mother must have felt when she would have realised that his son had one more best friend now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His mother was long gone before he’d even think of proposing Vaidehi to marry. It was the same girl, the only girl he’d ever spoken two words to. He left his mother’s house and starting living with her at a completely new place. &lt;em&gt;‘I’ve kept your lunch in the kitchen, heat it carefully, okay? I’ll be back by 7&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;, she used to say every morning to him, like a mother warning his kid before herself going out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from his “work from home” job, he was passionate about clicking pictures. Or rather, he liked to save the moments he was enjoying with her. Some days, he used to shuffle between them, recollect the memories, shed a few tears, curl up on the bed and just wait for her to come in the evening. He was also good at dodging off important calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best were the college days, when he started perceiving how real, the real world was. He was afraid on the first day. Four years later, he had a job, a “work from home” job, a girlfriend, and no family. But he had learnt how to ignore bullies and be in love, or at least that’s what he’d think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Come in the City Hospital ASAP. Your wife is here.’&lt;/em&gt; Some lady spoke on the phone. The call was from Vaidehi’s number. He rushed out, alone in the traffic and around so many people. He was little mad at her, why she didn’t take time off work during her last months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘It’s a baby girl’&lt;/em&gt;, The nurse announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Let’s call her Gayatri’&lt;/em&gt;, Vaidehi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘That’s a beautiful name’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘It’s your mother’s.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Oh yes. Of course.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Judge broke the nip of the pen, he declared : 
&lt;em&gt;‘According to the evidences presented by the accused himself and his self-admittance, the suspect, on charge of murdering his wife and his baby child, is hereby sentenced to be hanged till death on the month’s last day at sunrise. May God have mercy upon his soul.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was drunk. One day, when she came home. Or maybe high, he could not figure, he remembers, during college days, she had mentioned one of her female friend who was into heroin at those times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vaidehi’s call history. Her friend’s name in recent calls. She was definitely high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He could not dare speak a word to her. He made sure the little girl is fast asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She started abusing herself on daily basis. He was worried. He considered himself to be at fault. Maybe, she was not enjoying with him as much as he was. Maybe she didn’t love him like he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Nah! That can’t be it.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gayatri got into kinder garden. More house chores. Vaidehi couldn’t find time to visit her friend these days. She did go to work, but usually cut short her work hours in the evening. She was not happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘I will make her feel good.’&lt;/em&gt; Maybe one more kid? Maybe pregnancy will stop her from drugs? He knew if he’ll ask her, she would politely refuse or unwillingly agree considering her husband’s wish. Let it be an accident. Months passed, he started worrying. Nothing happened. How about a medical check-up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘I’m sorry sir, but you are infertile’&lt;/em&gt;, the doc said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within seconds, the first face to appear in front of him, was of his cute little daughter, Gayatri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call history. Her friend’s name is still there. Ring, ring. &lt;em&gt;‘Hello?’&lt;/em&gt;, a hoarse voice; shocked to the bottom of his hearts. It was of a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is about the night, the night he became the “accused”. Vaidehi was chopping off vegetables in the kitchen. He was looking at Gayatri, smiling, wondering. He could not hold any longer. He sneaked in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Hey’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*’Sorry I got late, had lots of pending work at office. Dinner would be ready soon. I’m preparing noodle soup and rice. *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘I had to talk to you about something. I am sorry.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She stopped. &lt;em&gt;‘What happened?’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘I am sorry, I checked your email.’&lt;/em&gt; His heartbeat racing fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Why the fuck would you do that?! And so what?’&lt;/em&gt;. She put the knife back on the table and stepped towards him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘I saw the notice from your office. They said you haven’t showed up in two weeks.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was Numb. His legs were trembling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Vaidehi, you love me right?’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Yes’&lt;/em&gt;, her lips were straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went straight to bed. Later that morning he woke up, to find himself alone. She was gone with Gayatri. The knife had cut real deep. It was a bloody mess. He fainted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What type of a person you are! That woman had no love for you, but why are you still doing this for her? Just go home already.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thick rope got around his neck. Eyes closed, hood on, memories started flashing in. And then came the regret, the regret that he would have loved Gayatri more, both of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For a handwash from a lamp, A Short Love letter</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/handwash-to-lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/handwash-to-lamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My beloved,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still remember the day when you first came in this house. You were inside the groceries bag which was kept on the floor right near my table. Ah! 36 aayi, 36 gayi but I never saw anyone like you. Your lean appearance, your light pink complexion and above of all, your aroma all blew up my mind. It took me only 8.2 seconds to realise that I was in love with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best incident of my life was yet to happen. I seemed to fall off when *Ramu kaka *took you out from the bag and placed you so close to me. I was breathing heavy. I felt as if a high voltage pulse entered me. I could notice all your features. Neck like a swan or even more beautiful, those elegant lips and yes, those tiny eyes, oh! I was feeling dizzy. For long you weren’t noticing me, maybe because I was not turned on. Thank god! Within few minutes the power was back and I lit myself as intense as I could. I felt more happy than I was before, more alive than I was ever. You had made an impact on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, our eyes met! I never felt so boozed up before then. Couple of my heartbeats were skipped. I was losing balance over the amount of current I was intaking. That made me fluctuate before you which would have hurt your eyes. But you kept looking at me or I should say I was getting nervous. Were you in love too? Did you like me too? But very soon you were carried away in the kitchen. You left me confused. And the sad part is, I never saw you even once since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, tonight it’s going to be the last night in my house. 3 days ago, our madam took a picture of me. I didn’t know why. Today I got to know that, I was sold, on OLX! Somebody will take me away in the morning. I hope to see you for the last time when I’ll be going. And for now, I’m going to think about you all the night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love you forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours and only yours, 
Mainstream FDS 500 GENIE 11W, 220V, E27 Bulb Base Lamp.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रानी (Rani)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/rani/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/rani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dedicated to all the nameless young girls out there in our villages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आज वर्षों बाद, रानी अपने मायके जा रही थी । ट्रेक्टर (गाड़ी) पर सवार , उसके साथ की औरतों को बड़ी अनूठी लग रही थी उसका बाहरी सजावट । भला एक हाथ में तीन चूड़ियां कोई पहनता है क्या ! &lt;em&gt;इसकी माँ ने इसे बताया नहीं कितना अशुभ होता है&lt;/em&gt; । दुसरे में चार थीं, दो लाल, एक पीली और एक हरे रंग की ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ गाँव की बहु हो का बिटिया ? ” ,&lt;/em&gt; एक बूढी औरत ने पूछ ही डाला।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ फुलिया मिस्त्री की बेटी हूँ । ”,&lt;/em&gt; रानी ने एक औपचारिक मुस्कान के साथ उत्तर दिया ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ हसनपुर वाले फुलिया मिस्त्री की ?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ जी ”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ बड़े विचारवान&lt;/em&gt; *रहलें तोहार पिता जी । महतारियो के भी बहुत बढ़िया सुभाव-विचार है तोहार । ”, *उस बूढ़ी औरत ने रानी के लिए थोड़ी सांत्वनाएं जुटायीं ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रानी जब छोटी थी तब उसके पिता जी का खेत में पानी चलाने वाले बोरिंग जनरेटर के साथ हादसे में अकाल मृत्यु हो गयी । रानी की माँ एक अत्यंत सरल और दयावान औरत थीं । गाँव में एक बेटे को ही असली वारिस समझा जाता है, लेकिन उन परिस्थितियोँ में भी रानी ने अपने पिता की अंतिम अग्नि खुद दी थी ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;हाई-स्कूल पर ट्रेक्टर (गाड़ी ) ने लाकर छोड़ दिया । अपना थैला उठाके , वहाँ से वो अपने हवाई चप्पल को धीरे — धीरे मिटटी के बने एक-पगिया रास्ते पर रखते हुए, अपने घर की ओर चल दी । शाम का वक़्त था , गाँव के बुजुर्ग घर के दालान पर लकड़ी के बने मचान के ऊपर रेडियो लिए विविध-भारती का सीधा प्रसारण सुन रहे थे । औरतें दीये , लाल्टेन इत्यादि जला कर , सभी घरों में रौशनी दिखा रही थीं । बूढ़ी औरतें लोटे में पानी भर कर , उसको हाँथ की उँगलियों से ढक के, आँगन में थोड़ा — थोड़ा पानी छिड़क रही थीं। न जाने कितने दिनों बाद रानी को वो भीनी खुसबू नसीब हुई होगी । कुछ दालानों पर मास्टर जी कुर्सी पर बैठ के कुछ बच्चों को गणित का पहाड़ा याद करवा रहे थे , तो कहीं कुछ लड़के ताश का खेल खेल रहे थे। तभी रानी के पैर किसी चीज़ से भिड़ गया । नीचे मुड़ के देखा तो मिटटी में लिप्त एक खिपली (ईंट का टुकड़ा) पड़ा था। उसे देख रानी के मन में न जाने कितनी यादें फिर से सांस लेने लगीं। कुछ देर के लिए मन दौड़ पड़ा , उसी खिपली को हाँथ में लिए , बाल की दोनों चोटियों को हवा में लहराए , एक बारह साल की रानी बन जाने को। गाँव का एक बहुत ही प्रसिद्ध खेल है किथ — किथ जिसे अंग्रेजी में hopscotch या stapoo भी बोलते हैं, जिसे एक पैर पे खड़े हो के , एक खिपली के सहारे खेला जाता है। कोई ठोस वजह तो नहीं लेकिन यह खेल लड़कियों में ज्यादा प्रचलित है।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उस खिपली को अपने पर्स में रख कर रानी अपने घर की और बढ़ी। आकाश छूता शीशम का पेड़ और गेंदे की फूल की खुसबू से कोई भी फुलिया मिस्त्री का घर पहचान ले । खुर्पी — कुदाल के सहारे अपने हाथों से बनाये हुए छोटे खेत में उसकी माँ ने बैंगन , मूली , मिर्च आदि उगा रखे थे। वहीं मचान पर माँ ने शायद कुछ बना के सूखने को दे रखा था. “*पापड़ मालूम पड़ता है।”, *मन में सोचते हुए रानी अंदर घुसी तो देखा माँ पड़ोस के किसी लड़की के साथ, चौखट पर बैठ के लूडो खेल रही थी। माँ का लूडो बोर्ड अब भी वही है, बस उसपे अनगिनत सेलो टेप की सजावट है ।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ अरे रानी तू ! कैसे आना हुआ रे ? एक चिट्ठी से संदेशा भी नहीं भिजवाया तूने तो। आ, बैठ। “&lt;/em&gt;, माँ चटाई पर से उठते हुए बोली।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;पड़ोस वाली लड़की लूडो समेट कर अपने घर को चल दी। वहीं माँ का चेहरा इस उम्र में भी छोटे बच्चे की तरह खिल उठा था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“रुक मैं अभी निम्बू तोड़ के लाती हु, सरबत बनाने के लिए “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*“अरे माँ , रहने दो न “ *— जब तक रानी कुछ बोल पाती, बिना चप्पल पहने ही ,उसकी माँ निम्बू तोड़ने के लिए घर के पीछे वाले बागीचे को प्रस्थान कर चुकी थी।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रानी ने अपने हाथ पैर धुले, भगवान् घर जा कर कुल देवी और अपने पिता की तस्वीर को नमन किया, फिर रसोई घर से एक कटोरे में दो ग्लास पानी भर लिया। एक नज़र दौड़ाया तो उसे चीनी का डब्बा दिखा। मात्र आधे चम्मच चीनी शेष थी उसमें।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उस सरबत को तो माँ के प्यार ने मीठा बनाया था।&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;रानी शाम ढलते ही अपने बचपन की सखियों के घर चल दी। आज न जाने कितने दिनों के बाद उसे अपने सर पे आँचल की फ़िक्र नहीं थी और न ही घर वापस आने की जल्दी।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>मसान (Masaan)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/masaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/masaan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;तसव्वुर से उसके ही &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;कुछ, यूँ उतर के तुम &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उसके नज़रों से छल करती ,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आज छज्जे पे बैठ के उसके &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;दिल का, अकस्मात् &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;टोह क्यों ले रही&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;याद है वो मेले में &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इनायत थी मिली उसे &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो गुब्बारों की सनसनी दौड़ में &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आतिशबाजियों के बीच &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मन विक्षिप्त कर दिया था तुमने&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जब संगम के किनारे &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उस शांत&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;मदमस्त हवा के बीच &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सलीके में &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लब काँप उठे थे उसके&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;प्रेम की चरमसीमा थी वो &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;या अमरसंगीत का शुभारम्भ &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जब घाट पर उस दिन &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तुम्हारा मोती चुरा कर उसने &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अपनी रूह के संग&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जलाया था तुम्हे&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;उन्हीं लबों से उसने &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सुरा उतारी थी भीतर &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;वो दोस्त ही तो थे &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;जो प्रेम के छाये में भी &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;सूरज को मुट्ठी में लिए फिरते थे&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आओ उड़ चलें फिर &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;इस मसान से कहीं दूर &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;लौट आएंगे जब &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;तुम थक जाओगी &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;अकेले गोते लगाते लगाते&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh, Today is Diwali? Happy Diwali !</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/diwali/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/diwali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;First brush your teeth, then touch anything,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; Mommy used to say whenever I tried to sneak in to the kitchen for the Diwali sweets. Today, as I woke up at 8:30, nothing replaced my butter bread breakfast combination. And when I checked my facebook, it reminded me that today is Diwali! So, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Happy Diwali friends&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; is going to be my status too, as if just to tell &amp;lsquo;em that I am celebrating too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing is that even today happiness is alive. But the meaning is not the same. Earlier it was mainly because of the fest, today it&amp;rsquo;s because of the one day holiday it rendered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made phone calls to my elder ones, touched their feet and received valuable suggestions to burn the crackers carefully. I know Dada ji had said exactly the same words somewhat 12 years ago. Who knows in advance that the childhood Diwali are the best ones we ever see in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at IIT Kharagpur, we have something called Illumination on Diwali. More than a thousand diyas are used by a single hostel to create amazing designs. Here are some of their pictures. That&amp;rsquo;s the only exciting thing I&amp;rsquo;m feeling about this Diwali.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;As there is so much light outside, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the need of putting any diya. As there is so much noise inside, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the need of burning any cracker.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some photos of Diwali celebration at IIT KGP: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=diwali+illumination+iit+kgp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.google.com/search?tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=diwali+illumination+iit+kgp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
