<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Letters on Himanshu Mishra</title>
    <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letters on Himanshu Mishra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Himanshu Mishra</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://orkohunter.net/letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter with no subject</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/letter-with-no-subject-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/letter-with-no-subject-1/</guid>
      <description>:name-retracted: wrote -  Hi Himanshu,
  Congratulations from the bottom of my heart for joining Spotify. We really miss you at college. You&amp;rsquo;re one of the few seniors at KGP from whom I got really influenced in making changes in my life. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of writing a letter to you since a few months as a chat/talk cannot convey the message with proper bandwidth. I wanted to talk about a lot of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Recommendation - Man&#39;s Search for Meaning</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>Dear :name-retracted:,
I finished reading a book today. It’s called Man’s Search for Meaning, written by Viktor Frankl. He was a German psychiatrist captured by Hitler’s army in one of the most horrific concentration camps. If you are not aware of “The Holocaust,” more than a million people were killed in those concentration camps and more than ten million Jews during World War II. In the Auschwitz concentration camp, he (the author) witnessed so many deaths and brutality during the time he was captured in prison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Psychedelics</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/on-psychedelics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/on-psychedelics/</guid>
      <description>I wrote - Hello :name-retracted:!
Last night, I watched the movie Her. It was a fascinating movie on emotions and AI. It was one of its kind and made me think a bit. Humans created a consciousness in the movie, and at one point it started wondering about itself.
Maybe a lot of humans, at some point in their lives, think about the purpose of their lives (Hilariously reminds me of &amp;ldquo;You pass butter&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is okay not to be special</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/it-is-okay-not-to-be-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/it-is-okay-not-to-be-special/</guid>
      <description>Hi :name-retracted:!
I hope I don’t bore you with this letter. I feel like talking to you about life. (Which I always want to do. All the time. It’s almost like I met you yesterday and quickly got comfortable in saying things.)
So. There we go. There is a married couple somewhere on the outskirts of a town, renting a one bedroom apartment in a 10-story dull looking building. They have a median family income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The era of fake acquaintance</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/the-era-of-fake-acquaintance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/the-era-of-fake-acquaintance/</guid>
      <description>I wrote Something provocative happened with me yesterday. I was with :name-retracted: in CCD after you left. We were there for quite some time. Meanwhile, a group of people came in, including a friend from TLS. I went ahead and had a brief conversation with him. But when I noticed, there was one girl in the group whom I also knew! You know her; she is the one from the early times of :group-name-retracted: (I think you met her on :place-name-retracted:).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response to &#39;How is Life?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/response-to-how-is-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/response-to-how-is-life/</guid>
      <description>I was asked &amp;ldquo;How is Life?&amp;rdquo; over chat by someone and I thought of responding with a letter.
 Hello :name-retracted:,
I am sorry it took me so long to respond to you. I was travelling. The same winter vacations, 30 days, and the curiosity of what to do with it. It&amp;rsquo;s astonishing for the old-me that I have no tech goals this time. I have been learning Guitar for a month and hence I tend to practice daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Metakgp</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/about-metakgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/about-metakgp/</guid>
      <description>You can listen to this in background Before The Beginning - John Frusciante (YouTube)
:name-retracted: wrote -  I wrote this couple of days ago, I wanted to send it to a private chat. But I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can, so I am sending it here. Of all people at MetaKGP, I surely think I can correspond freely with you.
  Hello :name-retracted:, :name-retracted: and :name-retracted:!
  I am writing this specifically for you guys because for me MetaKGP has always been defined by you three.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>