<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>letters on Himanshu Mishra</title>
    <link>https://orkohunter.net/categories/letters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in letters on Himanshu Mishra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Himanshu Mishra</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>

        <atom:link href="https://orkohunter.net/categories/letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />


      <item>
      <title>Book Recommendation - Man&#39;s Search for Meaning</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear :name-retracted:,&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;I finished reading a book today. It’s called &lt;em&gt;Man’s Search for Meaning&lt;/em&gt;, written
          by &lt;em&gt;Viktor Frankl&lt;/em&gt;. He was a German psychiatrist captured by Hitler’s army in one of the
          most horrific concentration camps. If you are not aware of “The Holocaust,” more than a million people were
          killed in those concentration camps and more than ten million Jews during World War II. In the Auschwitz
          concentration camp, he (the author) witnessed so many deaths and brutality during the time he was captured in
          prison. People were separated from their families and children. They were gassed up and killed if they were
          unfit for work. Surviving on very little food and medicines, all their lives were a misery. The author saw his
          companions losing hope for survival. Based on his own experience and the stories of his patients, Frankl
          argues that we cannot avoid suffering, but we can choose how to cope with it, find meaning in it, and move
          forward with renewed purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;To save you time from reading it, I will share the things I learned from this book.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;I see this book as an answer to “Why should we not be depressed?” and a guide to handling other
          existential questions. One of the most asked questions by the entire humanity is “What is the meaning of my
          life? What is the purpose of my existence?”. These questions have been here since tens of thousand years.
          People have created religions to answer these questions. Righteousness (Dharma) and other ethics come out of
          these religions. Here is what the author says -&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;There is no abstract universal meaning to life. We should stop finding it. We do not need to ask this
          question. But life itself is asking this question from us. We have to answer it ourselves. This question is
          not ours to ask, but for us to answer. We create our meaning. Whether it is work, love, or courage. We create
          our “Why” individually. And this “Why” guides us to survive any “How”.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;He adds that — &lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Life is not primarily a quest for pleasure or a quest for power, but a quest for meaning. The
          greatest task for any person is to find meaning in his or her life. It can be anything or anyone. Suffering in
          and of itself is meaningless; we give our suffering meaning by the way in which we respond to it.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Finally, something which I’ll always try to remember is — &lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Forces beyond your control can take away everything you possess except one thing, your freedom to
          choose how you will respond to the situation. You cannot control what happens to you in life, but you can
          always control what you will feel and do about what happens to you.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;This book is nothing but a relief, a motivation to lead a peaceful and meaningful life.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;When I thought upon how we are raised, I noticed that our parents, teachers, and well-wishers try to
          inflict us with what gave meaning to their lives. My grandfather found purpose in a well-paid job because he
          had a sizeable low-income family to feed. That was it. He is 88 years old now, and the meaning of life still
          hasn’t changed for him. My father finds the purpose of life in a loving family. Everyone should talk to each
          other and support each other in their difficult times. I don’t know why he does that, but that is what I am
          aware.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Neither of those two are correct nor incorrect. As an individual, I respect what drives them. But
          every time my grandfather says “I wish you get crores rupees of salary and stand 1st in your college”, I smile
          and silently disagree.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;So :name-retracted:, the next time you think of something which you have not achieved, which makes
          you feel you have not been successful, which threatens your self-esteem, take a minute and ask yourself “Is
          this or will this be meaningful to me?”. Meaningful doesn’t mean enjoyable but fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Take care,
          &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Himanshu&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>

      <item>
          <title>On Psychedelics</title>
          <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/on-psychedelics/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

          <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/on-psychedelics/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-wrote--&#34;&gt;I wrote -&lt;/h2&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Hello :name-retracted:!&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Last night, I watched the movie Her. It was a fascinating movie on emotions and AI. It was one of
              its kind and made me think a bit. Humans created a consciousness in the movie, and at one point it started
              wondering about itself.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Maybe a lot of humans, at some point in their lives, think about the purpose of their lives
              (Hilariously reminds me of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X7HmltUWXgs&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You
              pass butter&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;). I found myself in the situation for the first time right after JEE, but
              later I forgot as programming happened to me. And then, again after reading Sapiens this December. And
              now,
              it&#39;s stuck in my head. It&#39;s not always a negative thought, a lot of times I happen to be smiling
              and
              puzzled as well.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I&#39;m glad psychedelics exist in the world. It made me constantly aware of the mysterious and
              unknown, made me witness colors never seen before, geometries beyond apprehension, and gifted a broad
              palette of emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Often at times, I self-construct arguments against psychedelics being good and then later work on
              the counter-arguments. I have an interesting thought to share.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Think of our ancient tradition. Children during their brahmacharya were recommended to have a
              Guru.
              It was a norm to grow up having a guru. In the case of Eklayva, his teacher was a statue, not a living
              person. So, Guru was a concept but mostly found in the form of life. I highly recommend a thoughtful
              psychedelic experience to my friends once in life. I ask them to respect what they think of intaking. I
              believe these chemicals and plants have the potential to be the guru in this modern age. That is the
              thought. Also, not all teachers and teachings are good (thus, Bad Trips), but there is always a lesson to
              learn, always a lesson to think about.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;hr&gt;
              &lt;h2 id=&#34;name-retracted-responded&#34;&gt;:name-retracted: responded&lt;/h2&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;and gifted a broad palette of emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I believe the emotions I have collected from the small out-of-world experience I had is the best
              thing I kept with myself after the trip. Now I listen to the same music with more intense emotions. Now I
              live the same life with more vividness. (And the most wonderful thing about reading your mail is: I hadn&#39;t
              given many thoughts how these emotions emerged, I will now. Surely, these trips have changed my
              composition
              as human. (Romantic ahaa!))&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;We all have our unique mental models about the world and there are a lot of mental models trying
              to
              dictate our ways through life. (Most people aren&#39;t even aware of them. - I wasn&#39;t aware until I
              went
              for that Himachal trip).&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Example: the usage of &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo; everywhere is a small mental model about the
              world,
              watching a series of actions like a sequential programmer is another mental model, trying to optimize
              petty
              things, and watching people as a neural network model is another. We had these experiences and we have
              these
              models in our mind.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;These are the consequences of being from :state-name-retracted:, being a c++/python programmer,
              competitive programmers, deep learning engineer in the order the examples are given.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;And when I took pyshedelics, I created another mental model. It is about open-mindedness. It is
              compassionate and weak as a twig, at the same time it is strong as the storms. It embraces other mental
              models and tries to break them from bias.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Maybe if I hadn&#39;t taken it, I wouldn&#39;t have come out from the clutches of commitment.
              Staying in commitment for the sake of it is biased. (Commitment in itself is not).&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;When you are about to break a commitment, there is a lot of &amp;lsquo;socio-cultural&amp;rsquo;
              norms to stop you. More than anything, it is your mind asking you not to do it for the sake of &amp;lsquo;moral&amp;rsquo;
              compass you have set. Then you realize &amp;lsquo;love&amp;rsquo; is greater than any norms/compass and
              that
              love shouldn&#39;t make you feel mediocre. I realized I feel more loved(more dopamine) when I see the
              white
              moon by the trees than her (This was the snap moment, our last LSD trip). I had written a small sentence
              during those time:&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kahu kaise tujhe ki ek samandar se sukoon mila par dhoop nikalne pe wapas jana hai&amp;rdquo;
              (Hindi)&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;And it doesn&#39;t mean that you hate the ocean, that you have suddenly started hating it. It&#39;s
              just that if &amp;lsquo;love&amp;rsquo; is there, you&#39;ll carry the essence of the oceans within you,
              wherever you go.
              Everyone carries something, and you shouldn&#39;t carry the things just for the sake of
              carrying(commitment
              just for the sake of commitment) but only if you want to (love).&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I am always a tiny bit confused in this matter. There is yet some fingerprints on the glass, next
              psychedelic would help me get it cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;So here is how I used some open-mindedness I gathered from my trips. It shackled some norms set
              in
              my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I highly recommend a thoughtful psychedelic experience to my friends once in life.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Just to clarify, I would like to add a single point. It&#39;s for everyone but not &amp;lsquo;every&#39;time.
              I can provide almost anyone with an LSD but not DMT. Even :name-retracted:, I have never given him DMT. It&#39;s
              just that you have to feel (judge) whether they would embrace what they see. These are tough things we are
              looking at, it can make people but break them too.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I really believe you already know this but added for the sake of availability bias.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          </description>
      </item>

      <item>
      <title>It is okay not to be special</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/it-is-okay-not-to-be-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

          <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/it-is-okay-not-to-be-special/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi :name-retracted:!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I don’t bore you with this letter. I feel like talking to you about life. (Which I always want to do. All the time. It’s almost like I met you yesterday and quickly got comfortable in saying things.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So. There we go. There is a married couple somewhere on the outskirts of a town, renting a one bedroom apartment in a 10-story dull looking building. They have a median family income. (Imagine the couple in movie The Lunchbox). The family wakes up and goes to work. The wife prepares and sends him the lunchbox. And she always does thousands of other household chores, which look trivial but are as difficult as any job. The days are tiring. The couple gets together for dinner later in the evening. Let’s say they watch a movie, or a reality dance show with a celebrity guest, or maybe a scheduled TV serial, as usual. And this goes on for a long time. Like, really long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They constantly feel that something is missing. Suddenly, their lives look like an incomplete picture in front of them. They realize maybe they don’t have it all. So they decide to do what billions of us have decided in the past, i.e. to raise a kid. The kid gives them love to share in exchange for some financial load and a whole lot of time from both their lives. But they get happier, or maybe. Their lives go on, a bit busier than before. They are 3 people now. Everything is new to the child, so he/she is excited as hell. But the mundane stuff starts happening again. The dinner, the TV, the feeling of “something missing” from their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many of these families never figure out what was missing. I have seen a few. There are millions of them in our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this time, these people look at something only to realize, they don’t have it. They look at people in the movies/serials wearing clothes which they don’t have. The house, they don’t have. The parties they don’t go to. Or the romance, as shown in the movies. All of the mainstream media shows them things that they want, but do not have. But the worst part is, that the media tells them that those things exist and there is still hope, most of which is imaginary. So, they live in the expectation of achieving something which does not exist in reality or is too tedious to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have known this for a long time. But only now I realize, it’s very natural for us to do that. This has been going on for thousands of years. It’s called the human’s struggle for finding the meaning of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think we live with a purpose. And that we were sent with a purpose. We invented religion to make us believe that there is a white-bearded man above the clouds, always looking at us and that he loves all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when a self-awakened man comes and says, “You know what, we don’t exist with any purpose at all”. Or when Carl Sagan tells us about how vast our entire universe is and that we are nothing but pale blue dots in the whole picture; we feel so small. And that’s it. At this point, the one who realizes and accepts that we are not special, is known as a Buddha, and rest of us constantly miss out on life desiring to be special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is wrong with not being special?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why I am saying all this to you is that I don’t worry about our love not being what it isn’t. I am a simple guy, who thinks about the girl he loves when he wakes up and looks at her picture before going to bed in the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think as much as I accept this love as it is, the more joyful I can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bas itna hi kehna tha, kuch jyada shabdon mein :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Himanshu&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>

      <item>
          <title>The era of fake acquaintance</title>
          <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/the-era-of-fake-acquaintance/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

          <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/the-era-of-fake-acquaintance/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-wrote&#34;&gt;I wrote&lt;/h2&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Something provocative happened with me yesterday. I was with :name-retracted: in CCD after you
              left. We were there for quite some time. Meanwhile, a group of people came in, including a friend from
              TLS.
              I went ahead and had a brief conversation with him. But when I noticed, there was one girl in the group
              whom
              I also knew! You know her; she is the one from the early times of :group-name-retracted: (I think you met
              her on :place-name-retracted:). There was a brief moment of eye contact, but it instigated no emotion. I
              could not even say &amp;ldquo;Hi&amp;rdquo; because of the bland reaction on our faces.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;When we were leaving, we noticed that she was coming out of CCD too. From there to Veggies,
              :name-retracted: and I walked alongside her. I am not able to forget those 40 seconds; there was too much
              silence to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Now here is the deal. Somewhere in the datacenters of Facebook Inc, there is a matrix which
              stores
              the connection between two nodes, and the edge value of her and me is True. There have been numerous CSS
              divs containing strings or bytecodes which either she or I have written, which got a click from the other,
              sometimes a further div of &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; as well. Somehow, subconsciously my brain
              understood that this person and I had interacted a whole bunch and thus we are friends. But when the same
              mind physically spotted that same person for the first time in months, it was speechless.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;For centuries, there have roughly and popularly been two types of edges between homo sapiens,
              either they are acquainted with each other, or they are not. For the past decade, a third type has
              emerged.
              You know someone on Facebook, you &amp;ldquo;talk&amp;rdquo; to them, but you don&#39;t talk with that
              passion or eagerness to them in real life with using flesh and bones (Remember :name-retracted:?). For me,
              it is terrifying. What if people eventually stop using their mouth for conversations because Whatsapp and
              Messenger lets them use that gif meme to convey. What if we discover some other app or platform to express
              ourselves in the best way which is different than meeting the person and using our mouth, eyes, face,
              hands
              or smile to express?&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;And the fact that the first world countries already have incorporated a bit of this culture,
              simply
              raises questions on parenting. What if we are not concerned about our children, and the first friend they
              make do not physically exist around them. I am definitely not saying one is better than others, there are
              so
              many pros of the Scientific Revolution, Internet being a tiny monster of it. I am just saying that, are
              people responsible? Is Facebook responsible enough to know that it has created an illusion over
              friendships
              and relationship and does it care about it? From the weekly product and feature launches, for the sole
              purpose of us interacting more on their platform, and increasing their value as advertisers and not
              looking
              up from our phones, I think it does not care at all. Or is it in control of anyone to care about it?
              Something like a trained Deep Learning model, over which we only have very few control.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;From a curious homosapien, who used the internet to blab to you about internet. But yes, I know
              we
              have to have this conversation when we meet and this exchange of email shouldn&#39;t be the end, and that
              makes me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;hr&gt;
              &lt;h2 id=&#34;name-retracted-responded&#34;&gt;:name-retracted: responded&lt;/h2&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Hi!
              This predicament, as you are feeling, is understandable. The oddity of changing societal rules and
              relationships, brought about by social-media corporations, is at times overwhelming. But if you try to
              understand this phenomenon at an abstract level, then perhaps we can get a bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;What you have thought to be a &amp;ldquo;fake&amp;rdquo; acquaintance is not fake per se, but
              just
              another expression of the changes that are taking place in our society due to social media. It is at best,
              friendship in the normal sense of the word or at worst, a &amp;ldquo;virtual&amp;rdquo; acquaintance.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Humanity has come so far only because of the large-scale cooperations between diverse groups of
              people.This cooperation could be achieved, thanks to fictional stories like religions, society, and other
              collectivities which made it easier for people to trust each other. But as we all know, socio-political
              evolutions necessitated new stories to bind people together, and in the process, we developed theories
              like
              democracy, communism, nation-states to fit the narrative of the time better. So the critical thing to note
              here is that as the narrative has changed so have the rules governing the society.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;It is in this context that I want to place your qualms about the internet. The internet is
              undoubtedly forcing us to adopt a new narrative of our time and respecting the course of history over
              several millennia; we must be ready to accept this reality and better adapt to the changing times by
              altering the &amp;ldquo;rules&amp;rdquo; of the society.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Coming to the specific case of &amp;ldquo;acquaintance on the facebook but not in real life,&amp;rdquo;
              I do not find anything odd here. In fact, I find it empowering that acquaintances could be made even
              without
              knowing each other in real life. It is for the first time human-history that you can cooperate and
              collaborate with others, on a large and expansive scale, even without knowing them in real life. You don&#39;t
              need to have commonalities like religion, nationalities, ideologies and any other collectivities to come
              together and cooperate with each other. Cooperation is not predicated on external factors which are not in
              your control but internal factors that you can control. A person from Pakistan can send me a friend
              request
              on facebook, and if I want, I can become his friend and vice-versa. The acquaintance or the friendship, in
              this case, was established just because two persons wanted to become friends. How improbable this sounds
              without internet, in the complex realities of our time?&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Coming to your regret about not talking to them with the same passion in real life, I think here
              the critical factor being emphasized by you is the emotional content of these acquaintances. That the
              emotionality of it all is diminishing is what you want to say. But the emotion is just an after-effect. It
              is not the cause. You become friend with someone because you find something good in them for you and hence
              better cooperation. That in the end, you develop emotional attachments is just a side-effect in my view.
              Sometimes these emotions may create a feedback loop and ensure even better cooperation, like two lovers
              getting married. But unmindful emotions may lead to undesired consequences too, like hyper-nationalists
              going berserk in their common love for the country. I think, as long as the cause of cooperation is
              understood well, side-effects like emotions can be controlled or channeled in a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Techno-humanism aims to enhance human&#39;s life using technology and binds humanity in a novel
              way
              that breaks the shackles of boundaries between nations, religious differences, and any other differences.
              In
              this respect at least, social media like facebook, twitter have done well, irrespective of whether it was
              their motive or not. Traditional relationships which we are most familiar with are undergoing a paradigm
              shift, and it&#39;s again just a reflection of the changing times.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;It is getting long. :P I hope my ramblings did not bore you. Hope to have a wide
              discussion on it over a cup of tea sometime. :D&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          </description>
      </item>

      <item>
          <title>Response to &#39;How is Life?&#39;</title>
          <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/response-to-how-is-life/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

          <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/response-to-how-is-life/</guid>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I was asked &amp;ldquo;How is Life?&amp;rdquo; over chat by someone and I thought of responding
              with a letter.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Hello :name-retracted:,&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I am sorry it took me so long to respond to you. I was travelling. The same winter vacations, 30
              days, and the curiosity of what to do with it. It&#39;s astonishing for the old-me that I have no tech
              goals
              this time. I have been learning Guitar for a month and hence I tend to practice daily. On the other hand,
              I
              have goals of losing weight (lost 6 kgs in 45 days) and hence I&#39;m determined to maintain the daily
              calorie deficit. One of my cousin sisters at home (in :place-name-retracted:) gave birth to a little girl
              yesterday and I&#39;m planning to spend some time with them too! So yeah, this December it&#39;s mostly
              about being with close people and few goals which I&#39;ve wanted to achieve for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Lately, my thoughts have been revolving around this particular letter&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toptal.com/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;
              of Feynman. In which he says, &amp;ldquo;No problem is too small or too trivial if we can really do
              something about it.&amp;quot;. Reading this letter gives me tremendous relief because it settled down some
              of my uneasiness about something which relates to KGP itself. The general idea of MetaKGP as a group, for
              me, is a solution to the problem we have in KGP of closed societies and very little collaborative nature
              among a majority of people. (Of course, it means more). While I understood this problem very clearly,
              there
              is always more which have been troubling me since my first year. I still do not understand all of them,
              but
              few are &amp;ldquo;the troubled hierarchy and senior-junior relationship in our halls and societies&amp;rdquo;
              and &amp;ldquo;lack of human interactions about life and work both&amp;rdquo;. I always have so many
              people
              with whom I am able to talk about technology and so many other people with whom I am able to talk about
              philosophy, but I only have two or three friends with whom I can freely talk both at the same time, which
              in
              fact is the real me. And I always believed, for this to take place, we will have to do more than meeting
              online. (I am literally shaking at this point but this does not reflect on the words I have written so
              far.
              That&#39;s why I love human interactions more, where more senses are at work than just reading text)&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;At this point in time in my KGP life, I am certain that it is so much more helpful when you have
              good seniors with whom you can meet occasionally, curious peers with whom you discuss the questions. I
              have
              been blessed to get all of them, the likes of you and :name-retracted:. But this does not happen to
              everyone. I firmly believe there are people (like me) in my batch, who did not meet enough &lt;em&gt;[insert-an-adjective
              abstracted by &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo;]&lt;/em&gt; seniors (like I met) and now they come around and
              call
              a fellow friend &amp;ldquo;stud&amp;rdquo; while I just wish to join them and not create boundaries and
              levels between us. One of them ended his life ten months ago. And there are probably more living with the
              following thoughts. Just to add, I am absolutely not asking everyone to become a tech guy and get seniors
              who do open source. Few of the best people I have met in KGP do not belong to tech. And it should be like
              this.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;BUT, here is an interesting fact. A majority of my friends who are responsible, who try to
              understand about life, who are really enjoying this journey are associated with Collaborating in groups
              and/or doing Open Source software. And I believe this has to be one of the solutions for (some) people and
              could really help them. My motive to create a closed group of people who understand this problem and are
              willing to help others, the initiative of KWoC, the sessions etc. are just a bigger picture to my very
              small
              zeal of increasing more human interactions in KGP. It&#39;s disheartening when a lot of my friends do not
              understand the efforts or simply do not care.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Excuse me for some arrangement of words which can be put together in a more readable manner and
              losing my brevity. But I have not talked about this to anyone, except :name-retracted: and that too only
              once. It will take time for me to organize these thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;So, How is life?&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toptal.com/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lettersofnote.com/2015/10/do-not-remain-nameless-to-yourself.html?m=1&#34;&gt;http://www.lettersofnote.com/2015/10/do-not-remain-nameless-to-yourself.html?m=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;hr&gt;
              &lt;h2 id=&#34;response-from-name-retracted&#34;&gt;Response from :name-retracted:&lt;/h2&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Hey,
              Thanks a lot for writing this, the pleasure of receiving a letter isn&#39;t something I get often. So, How
              is life for me?&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Such broad questions are easy to ask and way hard to answer, that&#39;s why I mostly receive the
              answer &amp;ldquo;good!&amp;quot;. Right now I&#39;m listening to Blackstratblues, in another tab I have
              django documentation open which I have to use to complete to order to complete the screening process of
              Toptal &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toptal.com/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, and I have been thinking about ways
              machine learning is wrong I have attached a writeup. I just finished this book called &amp;ldquo;The Black
              Swan&amp;rdquo; by Nassim N. Taleb you should totally read it, on surface it is about limits of knowledge
              but I find him to be very profound and his philosophies connect everything in life and universe. He isn&#39;t
              a I know it all pundit rather he talks about what you don&#39;t know, what you cannot know and what can
              you
              do about it. Of course, as with any book and any author you don&#39;t have to agree with everything or
              even
              anything the author says but the book will give you a new perspective. I was about to say this perspective
              is &amp;ldquo;helpful&amp;rdquo; then I remembered my own writing on :blogpost-retracted:.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;The days just after quitting the job were pretty stressful, my parents even convinced me take
              back
              my resignation at one point, but now I&#39;m glad out of it. My biggest fear at job was that I&#39;ll get
              trapped in it, sure I didn&#39;t like it, I found it to be boring and whatever, but I know myself and I
              know
              that I adapt to things slowly as weeks turned into months, months would have turned into years and I would
              learned to like the job the way it is, extra money, suits, the &amp;ldquo;prestige&amp;rdquo; I had
              started
              to develop a taste for them. After sometime that fact that this job was something that I never wanted
              would
              have faded way and I would have accepted the most boring parts as part of the parcel, thinking what better
              can I get. Though it might not look that way from outside, quitting the job was REALLY hard for me, in
              conventional terms it was the best job I could have got, though I was very clear that this job was not
              something I wanted but the question was if not this then what? I saw no natural transition either, I
              interviewed with :company-name-retracted: for tech lead and they didn&#39;t take me. One day I was pretty
              frustrated, I thought if I don&#39;t quit now then I&#39;ll never be able to quit. I thought about the
              reasons I should stay, none of them were strong enough, so I resigned next day.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;About opensource, I don&#39;t have much to add to add to what you said. Just as you are glad to
              find us, I&#39;m glad to find you. As you did, sometimes I look back and realize that I have really really
              lucky. Things would have been way different if I didn&#39;t meet :name-retracted: and :name-retracted: in
              school, things would have been way different if I, :name-retracted: and :name-retracted: wouldn&#39;t have
              been my wingies, things would have been way different I hadn&#39;t discovered :name-retracted:&amp;lsquo;s
              blog before coming to KGP which lead to me to discover KLUG. There are many many such lucky things which
              have happened. Of course there are people who are luckier than me, but there are so many others who aren&#39;t.
              I think it is our responsibility to share this luck so that others can get a chance to get lucky like we
              did.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          </description>
      </item>

      <item>
          <title>About Metakgp</title>
          <link>https://orkohunter.net/letters/about-metakgp/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

          <guid>https://orkohunter.net/letters/about-metakgp/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;You can listen to this in background&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
              &lt;h2 id=&#34;name-retracted-wrote--&#34;&gt;:name-retracted: wrote -&lt;/h2&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I wrote this couple of days ago, I wanted to send it to a private chat. But I don&#39;t think I
              can, so I am sending it here. Of all people at MetaKGP, I surely think I can correspond freely with you.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Hello :name-retracted:, :name-retracted: and :name-retracted:!&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I am writing this specifically for you guys because for me MetaKGP has always been defined by you
              three. (+ :name-retracted: and Himanshu)&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I am writing this to talk about my tenure and how I feel about MetaKGP.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Starting from the very start, I always wanted to have a hacker experience. To learn and be
              someone who could build things to make one&#39;s life easier.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;In my first year, I refrained from joining other societies and went only for so-called technical
              societies, I always thought that we have a limited time and time spent on anything else would cut time
              given to my aim.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Then in the second year, being in :hostel-name-retracted:, Me and :name-retracted: found
              ourselves working together for OpenIIT Data Analytics challenge. I used to complete everything allocated
              to me. And maybe that&#39;s why :name-retracted: called me for a MetaKGP meetup. I was like damn, there
              are societies other than the research groups working in tech domain. :name-retracted: had asked me to
              write on the wiki about JCB, personally, I disliked it. Anyway, I completed it. And then wrote a little
              more on the wiki (I was copying what everyone was doing), but still the memories I cherished about MetaKGP
              came from the meetings we had, where we discussed possible projects. (I still think how crazy the idea of
              a 2.2 bot is.)&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Then I saw :name-retracted:&amp;lsquo;s :project-name-retracted: script, I was astonished how one
              can create sessions, log in to ERP and automate so many things. :project-idea-retracted:. I had made
              something of use, not only for me but for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Then there was a session on sys-admin by :name-retracted:, I tried to learn it, even practiced at
              room but couldn&#39;t get hold of so many things he talked about. I wouldn&#39;t try to justify myself
              here but would definitely say that it was my lack of interest that I didn&#39;t give much time to learn
              it. (At the time I was recently introduced to ML, had mentored the winter workshop on CV)&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Then came the third year, I think there was a phase shift. Suddenly we were focussing a little
              more on advertising MetaKGP. It is necessary that people get to know about MetaKGP and our projects, but
              we were focussed more on advertising than creating value. I am not undermining the ongoing projects,
              Naarad came to completion during this time, MFQP-source was going strong. But during this time only one of
              current third year told me during the meeting, &amp;ldquo;Ye meeting me bss fundebaazi chalti rahti hai&amp;rdquo;
              (He does not come to meeting now)&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Then came elections, :name-retracted: asked me and I stood up for contesting. At the same time,
              Inter-IIT and Inter-Hall OpenSoft were going on, I won&#39;t go into much detail but I was very busy. I
              wrote my proposal in a train journey and sent it to :name-retracted:, I believed that I was going to lose.
              Even in the vote, I gave myself lowest priority. But thank god I was chosen as a maintainer, I have
              learned so many things in my tenure.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;But this also meant that I had to fulfill what I had written in my proposal (Please don&#39;t
              rebuke on this point, I know it is naive of me to think so), So I started the
              :slack-channel-name-retracted: channel cause I knew that due to my interest I would read about ML and DL
              every day and hence posting regularly about it would be easier. And I conducted the
              :event-name-retracted:, I justified myself that I would get to know how senior people work and think. I
              learnt a great deal from the :event-name-retracted: but accepting their failure, none of them attracted
              more people to slack. Most of the people who came to :event-name-retracted: were on my personal
              invitation, even sharing from GymK page didn&#39;t help.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;In the summers, :name-retracted: had shifted everything to docker, I thought that this is the
              time that I can learn about docker and maybe help. I tried to install it, fix some issue. I got stuck
              somewhere and I left. It was frustrating to work on docker, I just accepted defeat that I won&#39;t be of
              much use for the server.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Now coming to this year: :name-retracted:, :name-retracted:, :name-retracted:, Himanshu,
              :name-retracted:, :name-retracted: and :name-retracted:, all of them had been great with me. But we were
              discussing more and working less. As I have fresh memories for this semester, I can recall that we talked
              about course reviews but never got them, we talked about a fresher intro we never gave, we talked about
              myriad things we never did. For me, this clearly shows how I failed as a maintainer. I didn&#39;t
              criticize anyone, this is not a good practice. I tried to work on projects: the :project-name-retracted:(a
              naive project), the :project-name-retracted:(it was almost completed, I mean it builds and runs, but as
              CIC already caches YT it is not of much use). We got traffic for MFQP-source (IMO this was awesome on the
              part of :name-retracted: and :name-retracted: for getting this feat). I contributed to the wiki, hoped
              that this might inspire people to contribute more.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;From my experiences, I would try to draw conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;It was foolish of me to believe that bringing more people on slack would help MetaKGP, Until and
              unless we create value there won&#39;t be much to bind us. I don&#39;t think we need a lot of people for
              MetaKGP if we have only 3-5 people from each batch that would be more than enough. We need to promote the
              Hacker culture in KGP, it doesn&#39;t specifically means promoting MetaKGP. We conducted few small
              lightning talk session amongst us friends this semester, I learnt a lot from that. We at MetaKGP need to
              stop branding ourselves as a society for everyone, We are (or have become) a technical society whose
              people have interest in everything. We need to focus more on projects, we, maintainers, created a small
              roadmap in our last meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;[Incomplete and left]&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;hr&gt;
              &lt;h2 id=&#34;i-responded--&#34;&gt;I responded -&lt;/h2&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Hey :name-retracted:,&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;It is hard for me to write the words I am about to. It is hard for me to maintain brevity due to
              multiple strong emotions attached to the subjects. But here I go.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;While reading your message, One thing that I felt is best described as Sorry. Yeah. I am sorry I
              did not support you enough on the cab ride with :name-retracted:, even when I wanted to. I am sorry I did
              not contest in the elections with you or justified my stance publicly of why not to. I am sorry I mostly
              acted as if &amp;ldquo;you are supposed to&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;I might voluntarily&amp;rdquo; for
              various tasks, events, and responsibilities. This is not how things work. On one hand, we are trying to
              get new and enthusiastic people, while at the same time, due to the same actions, MetaKGP is turning other
              people off, who already existed. I am one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Can I tell you something about Kharagpur Winter of Code? :name-retracted: has started growing a
              bad taste for it. His problem is &amp;ldquo;Why are we coaching people for GSoC? We should be promoting
              hardcore Open Source instead.&amp;rdquo; This is where I differ and agree with him at the same time. Yes,
              we should be promoting hardcore Open Source. But what would be the perfect strategy? Engineers with jobs,
              when they have an upfront deadline to ship a product and they need a simple NLP date time parser in
              Python, they don&#39;t go and write one library, they find it on GitHub, which saves their ass. And
              thereafter, when they create something useful, they return the favor to open source by maintaining
              projects like React, Angular, etc. So, the question is, why in this world, would any 18-year-old college
              student would do such thing? What is the value the kid sees? If you promote hardcore open source, 5 out of
              1500 would come and 1 would stay. If you promote Google Summer of Code, 400 out of 1500 would come and 30
              would stay. And out of those 30, you can definitely be certain that more than 1 would continue doing open
              source. So, this is what I said to :name-retracted:, &amp;ldquo;This is not a model which we invented for
              KGP, this is a model which Larry Page and Sergey Brin created in 2004. Even they resorted to money,
              incentives, and glamour to get more students into open source. We are still young, to solve this problem.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;One of my perspectives for MetaKGP is the same. It is trying to help students without giving any
              sustainable incentive, and hoping they would stick together. No, they won&#39;t. I still go back to the
              group because I know that some people in there share the same passion for Software as I do. Why are we not
              working on developing that passion? Why are we not passionate about creating things anymore? Small things,
              doesn&#39;t matter, but it should be solving the problem of at least one person. Let us do that! Let us
              empower more beginners to achieve this. Second years like :name-retracted: and &amp;ldquo;name-retracted:
              have such bright college life ahead, they do things which less than 1% of their batch would be able to
              comprehend. This is what we should be doing. And people like :name-retracted: and :name-retracted: are
              their inspirations when they do these things. The people who inspire them, just don&#39;t know how they
              are helping others without actually willing to.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I believe the &amp;ldquo;problem with MetaKGP&amp;rdquo; began when :name-retracted:
              misunderstood it. He started believing that promoting MetaKGP will solve all the problems because it
              represents the core concept of Freedom in software and a war against proprietary things (in this case,
              closed KGP societies and Hall culture). The concept of being open to everyone and hierarchy, all routed
              his passion towards promoting MetaKGP. It was hard to argue with him because he had forgotten what it
              feels to be the first year and knowing rat shit about these technologies and ideas. He had lost the
              concept of being a guide to juniors long time ago and he became a friend to everyone. Alas, that was never
              going to solve the issue. Willingly or unwillingly, everyone started spreading &amp;ldquo;word&amp;rdquo;
              about MetaKGP.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;But if you read :name-retracted:&amp;lsquo;s :article-name-retracted: you will find the motive
              &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;:exact-words-retracted:&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; For me,&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Collaboration comes when we work together to organize a big event, not one person contacting
              people to come and speak. Collaboration is when someone messages you &amp;ldquo;I will take care of this&amp;rdquo;,
              but you insist on sharing the work because you know they would get exhausted by the amount of work
              involved and they just said it because they are junior to you.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Openness is when we freely respond to juniors and batchmates &amp;ldquo;Yaar room pe aa ja kabhi
              bhi; Chal milte hain; Yaha se padh le&amp;rdquo;. Two days ago, I met 3 unknown juniors from RK. They
              wished to open a startup of memes. They didn&#39;t know what GET/POST requests are. I told them
              everything, how they can use MVC, databases, image editing with js, apps, security of servers. I left them
              with the suggestion, &amp;ldquo;Don&#39;t do this if you are aiming for users, do this because you want
              this product to be alive, do it just for the sake of creating it. Users will follow. And even if they don&#39;t,
              you&#39;ll never regret the fact of creating something.&amp;rdquo; I spent 2 hours with them and comforted
              them to approach me anytime in future. I guess that would be openness. I did not add them to KOSS or
              MetaKGP because it will not help them as of now, and they would probably be a victim of inferiority
              complex, as a lot of my friends were when I added them to KLUG in my first year. I was different and
              developed the false belief that this was the correct way and hence it would work for everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Self-improvement is when we read a trending article about git, python, (some particular ML
              algorithm) even if we know so much about it; because we thrive for that last 20-30% we don&#39;t know
              about it, that particular method or that command. And then we share stuff in places like ShowKGP.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Curiosity is asking :name-retracted: &amp;ldquo;how is work?&amp;quot;, even when your inner
              self is telling you that you would not get a constructive answer.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;In the :name-retracted:&amp;lsquo;s :article-name-retracted:, you can find an article about
              inclusivity - :exact-words-retracted:&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Alright, this is a good model. But it will fail when the &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; includes the
              one &amp;ldquo;who got into the phase of passive lack of exclusion&amp;rdquo;. Again, all I am resorting
              to is that promoting MetaKGP is a positive, attempt at solving a very difficult, abstract and huge problem
              in college. But no one ever questioned, should we really be doing that right now? For me, there are more
              existing problems in KGP which needs to be solved and they hold a higher priority. I have spent a lot of
              my time in KGP at solving those. You surely know all of it, and all of me in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Out of nowhere, this reminds me of the recent movie Newton. It is a great drama which shows us
              that there is a limit to the extent of solving a problem and strategizing is very important rather than
              following the pure true way. If you have watched it, you should remember the crazy scene when Rajkumar Rao
              holds the gun in his hand. If you haven&#39;t, I can quote a line from the movie &amp;ldquo;Sir, koi bhi
              change ek din mein nahi aata. Waqt lagta hai&amp;rdquo;. I can totally relate to :name-retracted:&amp;lsquo;s
              MetaKGP with the lead in the movie, who tries to solve everything instantly by doing it the pure way.
              Although it solves the problem upto some extent but is completely useless and can be solved in steps, in
              easier and more sustainable way.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I have been writing this email for a long time now, and I think it can never be completed. I&#39;ll
              get some tea now and hope to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;PS. I was listening to Post Rock the whole time. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;h2 id=&#34;name-retracted-responded--&#34;&gt;:name-retracted: responded -&lt;/h2&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Thanks Himanshu.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;At the first place, you don&#39;t need to be sorry for that. This incident has very little
              correlation to the cab discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;You have provided a more than verbose level of description, I would say -vv. And it resonates my
              own view.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;:some comments on the previous email:&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Oh this mail was such a great relief, few bad things happened these days and then you read a
              letter like this. I really liked the way you structured the letter, it seems like whatever is written are
              thoughts which came spontaneously to the mind but analysis which had always been there with ready
              references. &lt;em&gt;Chuckle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;I hope ki you are going good with the guitar!&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          </description>
      </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
