<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog posts on Himanshu Mishra</title>
    <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog posts on Himanshu Mishra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Himanshu Mishra</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://orkohunter.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Asynchronously</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/live-asynchronously/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/live-asynchronously/</guid>
      <description>Bringing the philosophy of asynchronous programming into life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining Spotify in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/spotify/</guid>
      <description>I have written about living in Japan, my work principles and what lies ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PEP8Speaks - Now helping 5,000 open source projects write neat and clean Python</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/pep8speaks-5000-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/pep8speaks-5000-projects/</guid>
      <description>I made the first commit to PEP8Speaks in Dec 2016. More than 5000 open source projects are now using this bot to write neat and clean Python. It is a free and open source software and financially sponsored by Python Software Foundation and Weblate.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BFS vs DFS in friendships</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/bfs-vs-dfs-in-friendships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/bfs-vs-dfs-in-friendships/</guid>
      <description>In real life friendships, some prefer Breadth First Search, but some fancy Depth First Search. BFS and DFS
are two search methods in Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/letters/</guid>
      <description>I made some of my letters and their responses public on my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We should write notes (for life lessons)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/we-should-write-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/we-should-write-notes/</guid>
      <description>During my JEE preparations, I used to make a lot of notes. Everyone did. Our Physics teacher was a storyteller. His stories used to make me wonder. I used to write them down as well.
I studied for two years. Thus, it was very important to write things down and keep revising. It was impossible to remember the lessons we learnt, without making good notes. My academic journey is about to end with my graduation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geniune Love and Infatuation</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/love-and-infatuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/love-and-infatuation/</guid>
      <description>After a long time, I read something so meaningful on reddit. How do you distinguish genuine love for someone from infatuation? was the question.
And I want to quote what I read and later express some of my thoughts on the subject. Here is the original comment.
 This is a good question.
  &amp;hellip; It’s really easy to confuse it with genuine love. But for me anyway, infatuation is a lot more like a drug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>और तसवीरें आने को हैं न !</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/aur-tasveerein/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/aur-tasveerein/</guid>
      <description>You can listen to my naratted version on Youtube.
 जो इन रंगों से कागज़ तुम सजाते हो,
जो ये सुन्दर रंग-चित्र तुम बनाते हो,
तुम्हारे मन में अभी
और तसवीरें आने को हैं न !
. जो मधुर गीत ये तुम सुनाते हो,
धुन ये प्यारी गुन गुनाते हो,
तुम्हारे दिल में अभी
और तरंगें बजने को हैं न !
. जो ये प्यारी बातें उसे बताते हो,
जो ये सुन्दर सपनें खुदको दिखाते हो,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/threads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/threads/</guid>
      <description>“You’re an interesting species. An interesting mix. You’re capable of such beautiful dreams, and such horrible nightmares. You feel so lost, so cut off, so alone, only you’re not. See, in all our searching, the only thing we’ve found that makes the emptiness bearable, is each other.” — Carl Sagan
 I always wonder when I listen to this quote in the song Doves by We Are All Astronauts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeking over what people search on DC</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/peeking-over-dc-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/peeking-over-dc-search/</guid>
      <description>IS THIS EVEN POSSIBLE?
 Well, Yeah.
 BUT YOU PROBABLY NEED TO BE A DC ADMIN TO GET THIS, NO?
 Nope. Anyone can do it.
 Holy Schnikes!!!! TELL ME HOW TO DO IT ON DC++!!
 Lol, come to Linux already!
 Note: I shall not be giving out a one-click solution to monitor DC searches intentionally even if it were possible. But if you are dedicated enough, you can figure things out by reading it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain, Mind and Consciousness — Essay</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/brain-mind-and-consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/brain-mind-and-consciousness/</guid>
      <description>Layers of ‘I’ when perceiving anything which is external to it
 Thanks to Montaigne, one of the first essay writers, for popularizing this literary genre. As the title suggests, I have had many musings upon the similarity and the differences of these three entities which can be thought as a subset of ‘I’ and which have very diffused boundaries among their definitions.
Disclaimer: The following ideas are highly subjective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DeleteFacebook</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/delete-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/delete-facebook/</guid>
      <description>After letting Facebook Inc. build a vast profile of me for 9 years, I deleted my facebook account. Privacy is not my only concern, but I personally reacted to how Facebook has affected the way we interact in our real life.
How?   Downloaded a copy of my data from facebook -&amp;gt; settings This contained all of my messages, photos, videos, and probably a lot more information which I can not consciously recall sharing with Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Discovery of pseudo-Acquaintance</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/pseudo-acquaintance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/pseudo-acquaintance/</guid>
      <description>It’s the dawn of the 20th century. If we pick two homo sapiens on earth, we can classify their relationship as one of these three types:
 An Acquaintance (Both of them are acquainted with each other) Unfamiliarity (No one knows about the existence of other) Celebrity status (One of the two is famous)  Today is the dawn of the 21st century. And every day in my college I meet few people who fall in none of the three types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of Public Posts: Twitter vs Facebook</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/twitter-vs-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/twitter-vs-facebook/</guid>
      <description>What design tells you about the company’s values
 Both Facebook and Twitter allow posts to be publicly accessible by people who have not joined the platform. It is good to note that the default setting of Facebook is to be private with posts and Twitter to be open to the web. While managing the Facebook and Twitter account of an organization I am involved in, I noticed a serious design pattern involved in displaying the public posts and their stark differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quest for Universal action — Essay</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/quest-for-universal-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/quest-for-universal-action/</guid>
      <description>You may listen to this while reading We Are All Astronauts - Ether (YouTube).
Few months ago, a significant percentage of my peers were involved in the process of getting a job or an internship, including me. Some got the success while some are still trying. But to my astonishment, I found that the degree of comfort in each one of them was not as expected. What I mean by that is, not everyone who got this success was happy, and not everyone who failed was sad, although the majority was skewed on the side of the former case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python&#39;s easter eggs and hidden jokes</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/python-easter-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/python-easter-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Just when you thought, Python could not be more fun.
 Read on GitHub https://github.com/OrkoHunter/python-easter-eggs
1. Hello World &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import __hello__ Hello World 2. The classic &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import this The Zen of Python, by Tim Peters Beautiful is better than ugly. Explicit is better than implicit. Simple is better than complex. Complex is better than complicated. Flat is better than nested. Sparse is better than dense. Readability counts. Special cases aren&#39;t special enough to break the rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons for creating good open source software</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/lessons-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/lessons-open-source/</guid>
      <description>I was reading about The Cathedral and the Bazaar, a book by Eric S. Raymond on various (open source) software development methods. The wikipedia page for the book in short, lists few important lessons that he learned and they can not be more true.
  Every good work of software starts by scratching a developer’s personal itch.
  Good programmers know what to write. Great ones know what to rewrite (and reuse).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>धुआं (Dhuaan)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/dhuaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/dhuaan/</guid>
      <description>ग़र्द उड़ाते उन पहियों को
हर सांझ हथेली मार - मार
सड़कें जो नापी सब ने ;
उस धुएं में छुपे
सत्य की परवाह थी क्या किसे ?
. ढलते उसी वक्त में
चूल्हे में गोयठे सुलगाती
हज़ारों बार आँखें सेंकी ;
उन अगणित माताओं के
नयनों की परवाह थी क्या किसे ?
. उन्मुक्त मित्र-मंडलियों संग
जब धुएं में विलुप्त अंतर्मन
फिरदौस की सैर हम करते ;
तब दिल में उस बुझते</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I hate my friends on Instagram?</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/instagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/instagram/</guid>
      <description>Watch this video from Nerdwriter1 Let&amp;rsquo;s Fix Instagram (YouTube).
Instagram is Facebook, but only with a different purpose than connecting people, it’s about sharing photos. Photos are great, they convey art, beauty and literature in its own form. And that is what attracted Instagram to so many users. But the problem started when, we applied our *minds to it.
What Instagram should never be about   Sharing pictures with your face in it Couple years ago, if you had clicked a great picture of yours and you wanted to share it among your friends (people who know you), you’d usually go to Facebook and then share it over there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep : A personal shell command keeper</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/keep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/keep/</guid>
      <description>A Meta CLI toolkit  Writwick Wraj loves using the command line. Writwick googles “How to do X in terminal?” and multiple forums and blog posts finally provide him the magical command for the rescue. Problem Solved ! Fast forward couple weeks, Writwick has to do X in terminal, again. Wraj remembers solving this few weeks ago. Let him do a reverse-i-search with Ctrl+R. Nope, can’t remember sh*t. Browser search history?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection of Linux fortunes ❤</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/linux-fortunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/linux-fortunes/</guid>
      <description>fortune | cowsay  This is about how I maintain the space https://github.com/OrkoHunter/mfdf/blob/master/fortunesfortune is a Unix program which chooses a random message from its database of quotations and displays in the Shell. There are mainly three types of the quotations; literature, fortunes and riddles. I once tried adding fortune in my ~/.zshrc file so that a new fortune would appear whenever I create a new terminal session. There are many other places for making it appear e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick guide to git and github (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/quick-guide-to-git-and-github-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/quick-guide-to-git-and-github-1/</guid>
      <description>Before we start, make sure you have an account on GitHub. Go to https://github.com. Pick a username, enter your email id and choose a password. Next, choose unlimited personal repositories for free. In the final step you can give some input to github and voila ! You are now a github user. (If you are redirect from KWoC, use the username there.) There is plethora of git guides over internet, some are really good and some really suck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आंसुओं के बिंब से छलकती हुई दुनिया, देखी थी मैंने एक बार</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/aanshuon-ke-bimb-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/aanshuon-ke-bimb-se/</guid>
      <description>आंसुओं के बिंब से छलकती हुई दुनिया, देखी थी मैंने एक बार
वक्त की गहराईयों में डूबती नज़र आई थी वो
नज़रों से सहारा दिया मैंने
ख़ुशी का भरोसा दिया मैंने
न जाने मेरा हाथ क्यों न थामाँ उसने
उसे गहराइयों की सुकूँ भाती चली गयी ।
. Thanks to Sandeep Jha for the first two lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erotomania : An Unfortunate Tale</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/erotomania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/erotomania/</guid>
      <description>“Hey Wake up!
Wake up, for you are left with just 30 more minutes.
You better sleep after this is over; rather that would be your only choice. Just 30 minutes later, when the crescent rays will fall on the black hood covering your face, when you’ll be tied with, or rather “in” a knot, for the second time of your life, believe me you would not want to be in haste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For a handwash from a lamp, A Short Love letter</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/handwash-to-lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/handwash-to-lamp/</guid>
      <description>My beloved,
I still remember the day when you first came in this house. You were inside the groceries bag which was kept on the floor right near my table. Ah! 36 aayi, 36 gayi but I never saw anyone like you. Your lean appearance, your light pink complexion and above of all, your aroma all blew up my mind. It took me only 8.2 seconds to realise that I was in love with you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2016 Report : Stingray</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/gsoc2016-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/gsoc2016-report/</guid>
      <description>It began 5 months ago, in February. Due to my recent interests in Image Processing, I had made few Pull Requests to the scikit-image library, but it did not participate in GSoC. And that, after all those years of consecutive partcipation! (Yes I felt little sad.)
So, the day when Google announced the list of organizations, I started my “org hunt” ! And by the end of the day, I had sorted out the Python-only projects, which included the project Library of Time Series methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing and Re-Gaining trust on .gitignore</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/losing-and-regaining-truct-on-gitignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/losing-and-regaining-truct-on-gitignore/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share an interesting story of a problem which I’ve faced many times since I started using git. This story is about “losing and re-gaining trust on .gitignore”.
Event : Create a Python app. Run it, test it and Boom! Now it’s time to push it to GitHub.
git init . git remote add https://github.com/iamsosmart/notsomuch.git git push -u origin master Shit, Shit, Shit ! I wasn’t supposed to push the pyc files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do I do when I’m bored from studying (or not studying) for the exams?</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/ping-me-and-keep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/ping-me-and-keep/</guid>
      <description>The semester is about to end and I have no clue about what is going in the end semester examinations. I have been studying a good amount of complicated Mathematics. I usually lose my temper studying my other subjects like Environmental Science, Biology and Economics. For how long will I have to study “everything”. Sigh.
So, I either eat or surf the web when I’m not studying. That’s pretty much it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Sublime Text not something to be frowned upon?</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/sublime-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/sublime-text/</guid>
      <description>There have been people, advisers, and more people, enlightening the fact about “real programmers”, they use emacs or vim.
‘I use sublime text’, is often misunderstood as ‘I am a novice and I don’t like pure black window’. There is no way this 7 years old editor is going to compete with 39 years old emacs and 15 years old fork of yet another 39 years old editor vi. Nevertheless, there’s much more to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रानी (Rani)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/rani/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/rani/</guid>
      <description>Dedicated to all the nameless young girls out there in our villages
आज वर्षों बाद, रानी अपने मायके जा रही थी । ट्रेक्टर (गाड़ी) पर सवार , उसके साथ की औरतों को बड़ी अनूठी लग रही थी उसका बाहरी सजावट । भला एक हाथ में तीन चूड़ियां कोई पहनता है क्या ! इसकी माँ ने इसे बताया नहीं कितना अशुभ होता है । दुसरे में चार थीं, दो लाल, एक पीली और एक हरे रंग की ।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>मसान (Masaan)</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/masaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/masaan/</guid>
      <description>तसव्वुर से उसके ही
कुछ, यूँ उतर के तुम
उसके नज़रों से छल करती ,
. आज छज्जे पे बैठ के उसके
दिल का, अकस्मात्
टोह क्यों ले रही
. याद है वो मेले में
इनायत थी मिली उसे
जो गुब्बारों की सनसनी दौड़ में
आतिशबाजियों के बीच
मन विक्षिप्त कर दिया था तुमने
. जब संगम के किनारे
उस शांत
मदमस्त हवा के बीच
सलीके में
लब काँप उठे थे उसके</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh, Today is Diwali? Happy Diwali !</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/blog/diwali/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/blog/diwali/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;First brush your teeth, then touch anything,&amp;quot; Mommy used to say whenever I tried to sneak in to the kitchen for the Diwali sweets. Today, as I woke up at 8:30, nothing replaced my butter bread breakfast combination. And when I checked my facebook, it reminded me that today is Diwali! So, &amp;ldquo;Happy Diwali friends&amp;rdquo; is going to be my status too, as if just to tell &amp;lsquo;em that I am celebrating too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>