<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on Himanshu Mishra</title>
    <link>https://orkohunter.net/categories/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on Himanshu Mishra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Himanshu Mishra</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://orkohunter.net/categories/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Naval Ravikant on JRE</title>
      <link>https://orkohunter.net/notes/naval-jre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orkohunter.net/notes/naval-jre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3qHkcs3kG44&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3qHkcs3kG44&lt;/a&gt;
(Lots and lots of wisdom here. And it&amp;rsquo;s easy to listen to him.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specialization is for insects. You&amp;rsquo;ve got one life to do all you want to do. Humans are multi-variant.
Every human is capable of all the experiences. We will have to dare to look fool if we want to start
over in something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Modern Struggle&amp;rdquo; is no longer the disease of scarcity, but it&amp;rsquo;s a disease of abundance.
On one side there are scientists, researchers, billions of dollars of creating addiction machines (Media, Technology, Food) vs You.
And you are alone in this fight. A short clip here with sketches from After Skool &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OqlfWDyS1Io&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OqlfWDyS1Io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would rather read 100 books over and over again, rather than read all the books. We have a finite memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been automating and eliminating jobs since forever (like when Electricity was invented). We don&amp;rsquo;t lose jobs,
we start doing only the most creative jobs. The ideal world is where there are only &lt;em&gt;creative&lt;/em&gt; jobs, and all non-creative
jobs will be automated by machines. e.g. Identifying problems and thinking about solutions in a specialized field is a
creative job. Making art is a creative job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meditation is really doing &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not about focusing on the breath, that&amp;rsquo;s just the method which leads to the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness is peace in motion. When you are peaceful, it&amp;rsquo;s easy for you to start doing things and be happy. Short notes from himself. &lt;a href=&#34;https://nav.al/peace-motion&#34;&gt;https://nav.al/peace-motion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to be healthy, happy and rich. (Words have more deeper meanings from his point of view.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One desire at a time. Desires are fine, but we can&amp;rsquo;t fulfil more than one at a time. Is my posture correct, can I eat something now, what about the view, that message, this conversation, etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True curiosity is when you want to learn it and you&amp;rsquo;re not thinking about telling about it to people just that very moment. Good question to ask self: “Would I be still interested in this thing if I couldn’t tell anyone?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do things you love. Same philosophy as what Steve Jobs said in his Stanford commencement speech. If you don&amp;rsquo;t love the 8 hours work you do every day, that&amp;rsquo;s a huge waste of time in exchange of whatever money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What gets you motivated to things these days?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Art. This is art, talking to you. Art is just creativity, anything that gets done for its own sake. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing beyond it. Loving somebody, playing. Learning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
